<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
 This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site.
 It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content.
 You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another.
 This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site.

 To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps:
 1. Log in to that site as an administrator.
 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel.
 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list.
 4. Activate & Run Importer.
 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page.
 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users
    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an
    existing user on the site or to create a new user.
 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc.
    contained in this file into your site.
-->
<!-- generator="WordPress.com" created="2019-02-28 11:46"-->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/">
  <channel>
<title>sakyuuga memo</title>
<link>https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com</link>
<description/>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 11:46:30 +0000</pubDate>
<language>en</language>
<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
<wp:base_site_url>http://wordpress.com/</wp:base_site_url>
<wp:base_blog_url>https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com</wp:base_blog_url>
<wp:author>
  <wp:author_login>kyuudere</wp:author_login>
  <wp:author_email>sakyuuga@gmail.com</wp:author_email>
  <wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[kyuudere]]></wp:author_display_name>
  <wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_first_name>
  <wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name>
</wp:author>
<wp:term>
  <wp:term_id>1357</wp:term_id>
  <wp:term_taxonomy>nav_menu</wp:term_taxonomy>
  <wp:term_slug>primary</wp:term_slug>
  <wp:term_name><![CDATA[Primary]]></wp:term_name>
</wp:term>
<wp:term>
  <wp:term_id>1358</wp:term_id>
  <wp:term_taxonomy>nav_menu</wp:term_taxonomy>
  <wp:term_slug>social-media</wp:term_slug>
  <wp:term_name><![CDATA[Social Media]]></wp:term_name>
</wp:term>
<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://sakyuuga.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/cropped-ixoal3fj.jpg?w=32</url>
	<title>sakyuuga memo</title>
	<link>https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<item>
  <title>Anime Style Talk Event Notes (July 1st)</title>
  <link>https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/2018/08/01/anime-style-talk-event-notes/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 08:24:13 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>kyuudere</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/?p=46</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:justify;">This is a collection of notes by <em>sakuga</em> fans who attended Anime Style Talk Event on July 1st, which was hosted by <a href="https://twitter.com/animesama"><span class="st">Yūichirō</span> Oguro</a> and had guest speaker <a href="https://twitter.com/181ino">Toshiyuki Inoue</a> and Takeshi Honda.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-63" src="https://sakyuuga.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/talk-event.jpg" alt="talk event" width="1162" height="616" /></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Please note that I'm not a professional translator, Japanese and English aren't my first language, so there are bound to be a lot of mistakes or different interpretations from the original notes. A lot of re-arrangement and additional info have been made too.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I know this is <em>kuso </em>translation, I add a lot of my own interpretation and implication from the notes (the notes were posted on twitter so obviously they don't cover the whole conversation, it's just a summary). And probably there are some parts that I haven't translated yet. It's really my first poor attempt at translating from JP to EN like this, so I'd like to apologize first if this is really painful to read.</p>
But you can always read the original notes here:

https://pastebin.com/973qkyxp

Source: https://twitter.com/hdjxne3jagh7nsa

and here:

https://twitter.com/siromitu/status/1013729618900148224

Thank you for reading.
<p style="text-align:justify;">Additional note: There's another Anime Style Talk Event (and screening event for Maquia, MEMORIES, and Jin Roh) on July 21st, with guest speakers Toshiyuki Inoue, Takeshi Honda, and Hiroyuki Okiura. I'd like to translate it too if I have time, but I can't promise it will be done soon.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">======</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#7eb0e6;"><em><strong>Let's talk about Yutaka Nakamura</strong></em></span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Inoue</strong>: "Nakamura-san is really good, like, just by watching his animation makes me happy. His <em>sakuga </em>MAD are overflowing with such pleasantness."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Inoue</strong>: "His animation in Sword of the Stranger always bring so much joy to me, it is a must-see scene for animators/people who are aiming to be animator."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Oguro</strong>: "When animating, Nakamura-san always read the mood. Surely he likes playing around with the storyboard and instruction the director gave to him, but he still does it at the scope where it is allowed."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Note: Nakamura animated the climax battle between Nanashi and Luo Lang.</p>
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ukQnsxUs1Fw

&nbsp;
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Inoue</strong>: "Let's talk about his <a href="https://www.sakugabooru.com/post?tags=yutaka_nakamura+character_acting+">character acting animation</a>, even a simple movement is amazing. Technically speaking, I don't think our skills differ that much, but his inventiveness (at creating action movement) is outstanding. His amazing animation is a result of such outstanding skill and his passionate energy when drawing."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Honda</strong>: "There has been an increasing number of young animators who want to do flashy action like Yutaka Nakamura-san these days. But it's important to note that super animators like Nakamura-san also started from the bottom stage with simple character acting animation, there are many newbie who just want to skip this stage. You mustn't neglect this."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#7eb0e6;"><em><strong>About Inoue's animation characteristic</strong></em></span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Inoue</strong>: "I don't draw things that so out of place (strange). I'm able to draw animation in such a way that I desired."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Oguro</strong>: "Well, that's a bit cool. Wait...isn't it too cool? To be able to meet the direction's demand and even exceeds their expectation. Also you don't need any correction, do you?"</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Inoue</strong>: "Well, you can say that to be able to meet the direction's demand is also my aesthetic sense. Also, during the production of Ghost in the Shell, people at I.G said 'look, only Inoue-san's <em>genga</em> that aren't corrected'. "</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong><span style="color:#7eb0e6;"><em>Gu Gu Ganmo, one of Inoue's earliest work and where did his inspiration come from</em></span>
</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Oguro</strong>: "You really did well on Ganmo, not only your animation was able to meet production's demand, you also played with the movement and delivered cool action too."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Inoue</strong>: "I wasn't particularly thinking about direction nor the audience at the time, I just was doing whatever I wanted. It was the era where animators' characteristic were displayed directly through what they draw. They didn't draw with such a mind like 'what if it will be checked by other people (animation supervisors)'. For example in Urusei Yatsura, there were several people who followed in Yoshinori Kanada-san's footsteps and their animation really stood out."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Honda</strong>: "I decided to enter animation industry after I saw Ganmo. Inoue-san's <a href="https://www.sakugabooru.com/post?tags=gu_gu_ganmo+toshiyuki_inoue+">animation</a> were just different from other people's drawings and easy to spot."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><em>Inoue's part in episode 7, roller coast</em>er <em>scene.</em></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Oguro</strong>: "That scene was really impressive."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Inoue</strong>: "At the time I received a strong influence from Takashi Nakamura-san. The way he draws body's form and limbs is just so cool, and I hadn't seen something like that before."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Inoue</strong>: "Speaking of Takashi Nakamura-san, rather than AKIRA I always liked his Gold Lightan and Urashiman better after all. His solo episode on Gold Lightan episode 41 (<span class="st">大魔神の涙</span>) was really good. Although there were many production restrictions (to save money) during his solo episodes, like several cuts weren't used in photography process."</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PI_JOqRO1VE</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Honda</strong>: "Actually I've never seen that episode before."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Inoue</strong>: "Then prepare yourself for a slap on the wrist."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Oguro trivia</strong>: "Although Sushio-san really likes Takashi Nakamura's AKIRA, he has never seen Urashiman."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#7eb0e6;"><em><strong>From Ganmo to friendship with Hiroyuki Kitakubo</strong></em></span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Inoue</strong>: "After the broadcast of Ganmo's first episode, I was asked directly by <a href="https://www18.atwiki.jp/sakuga/pages/816.html">Hiroyuki Kitakubo</a>-san to show me the <em>genga </em>for <a href="https://www.sakugabooru.com/post/show/21369">my scene.</a> Since then we stayed in touch with each other and I got the chance to see many <em>genga </em>from another studio's (and freelance) animators, such as in Urusei Yatsura. Actually I traded my Ganmo <em>genga</em> with Kitakubo's collection, it was <a href="https://www18.atwiki.jp/sakuga/pages/55.html">Yasuomi Umetsu</a>-san's "Stop!! Hibari-kun!" <em>genga</em>."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">*Note: during the production of Urusei Yatsura, Kitakubo also did some KA for "Stop!! Hibari-kun!" episode 9 and 15, which had Umetsu as animation supervisor and key animator in those episodes.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#7eb0e6;"><em><strong>About Cream Lemon Part 4</strong></em></span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Inoue</strong>: "After Ganmo, we became really close and when Kitakubo-san invited me to his Pop Chaser episode."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#33cccc;"><span style="color:#7eb0e6;">Note: Inoue drew the H scene in the first </span><span style="color:#00ccff;"><span style="color:#7eb0e6;">half. [NSFW Warning]</span>
</span></span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Inoue</strong>: "It's necessary to make the individuals movement different when they are making out, and there's bed sheet too. I kinda want to compliment myself for figuring that out."</p>

<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:center;">https://vimeo.com/247650360</p>
<span class="st"> Cream Lemon Part 4: POP♥CHASER was released on March 13, 1985. It was Hiroyuki Kitakubo's first directorial debut, just when he was still 21 years old. He was credited under pen name Dai Sakura, with him providing the scenario, storyboard, direction, animation supervision, and character design (along with Yuuji Moriyama). </span><span class="st">Kitakubo's personal connection was truly integral role for this OVA, they were brought from various places, and not to mention that all of them were using pen names. You can say they were the memers of their generation. </span>

https://www18.atwiki.jp/sakuga/pages/219.html</blockquote>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Inoue</strong>: "You can say it was thanks to Kitakubo-san that I was able to broaden my world and meet many people. If I hadn't met Kitakubo-san probably I would've been stuck with Studio Junio for a few more years."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Note: Inoue later went outside of the studio to work on AKIRA when he was around 26 or 27.<a href="http://www.pelleas.net/aniTOP/index.php/toshiyuki_inoue_interview">*</a></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#7eb0e6;"><strong><em>MEMORIES</em> </strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Note: As a brief introduction, MEMORIES (also <i>Otomo Katsuhiro's Memories</i>) is a 1995 Japanese animated science fiction anthology film with Katsuhiro Otomo as executive producer, and based on three of his manga short stories. The film is composed of three shorts: <i>Magnetic Rose</i> (<span lang="ja">彼女の想いで</span> <i>Kanojo no Omoide</i>), directed by <a title="Studio 4°C" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Studio_4%C2%B0C">Studio 4°C</a> co-founder Kōji Morimoto and written by Satoshi Kon; <i>Stink Bomb</i> (<span lang="ja">最臭兵器</span> <i>Saishū-heiki</i>), directed by Tensai Okamura and written by Otomo, and <i>Cannon Fodder</i> (<span lang="ja">大砲の街</span> <i>Taihō no Machi</i>), written and directed by Otomo himself.<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Memories_(1995_film)">*</a></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Inoue served as character designer and animation supervisor for Magnetic Rose and key animator for Cannon Fodder, which were produced by <a title="" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Studio_4%C2%B0C">Studio 4°C. </a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V2WlqSwduzE</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Inoue</strong>: "I gave a lot of animation correction to the point I was re-drawing about half of the film from the scratch. Only <a href="https://www.sakugabooru.com/post?tags=magnetic_rose+hiroyuki_okiura+">Hiroyuki Okiura</a>-san and <a href="https://www.sakugabooru.com/post?tags=magnetic_rose+kouichi_arai+">Kouichi Arai</a>-san that didn't need any correction apart from character's face."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><em><span style="color:#7eb0e6;"><strong>Small talk</strong></span></em></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Inoue</strong>:</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">- "I kinda want to participate in flashy anime."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">- "I don't have much interest in story, the only novel I ever finished to read is Ring."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">- "Manga is only a collection of pictures with words attached on it. If I read it and don't find it interesting I'll just flip the pages and gaze at the pictures."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">- "I don't have it in me, but Kenji Kamiyama can tell you the weak point of a story and why it is a poor piece of work."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">- "While I don't have much interest about story in anime that I worked on, I don't have such a thought that story is unimportant. Sometimes I thought, "before you drew good storyboard, how about to fix the story first?"."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#7eb0e6;"><strong><em>Inoue's Anime recommendation</em></strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>- Bambi</strong>.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Inoue's comment: even though the animation techniques hadn't been established at the time, from the perspective of animation technique, the form of animals brought big influences. There were no technical gap/weak points in it.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">- <strong>Fantasia</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Honda interrupted: "But Fantasia is boring."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Inoue: "Just watch it for its technical skill!"</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">- <strong>101 Dalmatians</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">"Around this era, Disney's style has been established."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">- <strong>The Secret of Nimh</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">"Personally I think The Secret of Nimh's average animation quality is the best in the world. In a work with no <em>sakuga kantoku </em>system, the animation's level and movement remained constant. Don Bluth's <a href="https://www.sakugabooru.com/post?tags=don_bluth+the_secret_of_nimh+">cool timing and character acting</a> (the great attention to detail how character moved) were so amazing that I tried to imitate his style."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">- <strong><span class="st">The Little Prince and the Eight-Headed Dragon</span></strong> / <em>Wanpaku Ōji no Orochi Taiji</em> [TOEI, <span class="st">1963, <em>Yugo Serikawa</em></span>]</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">- <strong>The Great Adventure of Horus, Prince of the Sun</strong> / <i>Taiyō no Ōji Horusu no Daibōken </i>[TOEI, 1968, Isao Takahata]</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">- <strong>Animal Treasure Island / </strong><i>Dōbutsu Takarajima</i> [1971, Hiroshi Ikeda]</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">- <strong>3000 Leagues in Search of Mother</strong> / <i>Haha o Tazunete Sanzenri</i> [1976, Isao Takahata]</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Main point: Produced by small number team, Miyazaki-san's layouts, Yoichi Kotabe-san's animation supervision. Not only that, the scenario and direction is still one of the best, the depiction of characters' personalities were so real.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">- <strong>Heidi</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">- <strong>Hedgehog in the Fog</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">- <strong>Emara</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">- <strong>The Old Lady and the Pigeons</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Inoue</strong>: "Also, I watched Enter the Dragon (Bruce Lee's film) around 30 times at the theater."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#7eb0e6;"><em><strong>Another trivia</strong></em></span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">There was a project called Sea Side Company, an anime pilot that was produced by TOEI. It was directed by Junichi Sato but the serialization plan cancelled and the pilot has never been released on physical copy either. The pilot film mostly animated by Inoue, with a bit of key animation by Satoru Utsunomiya and Yuuji Moriyama.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><em><strong><span style="color:#7eb0e6;">Animators that Inoue keeps an eye out for</span>:</strong></em></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">- <strong><a href="https://www.sakugabooru.com/post?tags=megumi_kouno+">Megumi Kouno</a></strong></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Inoue watched Darling in the Franxx episode 3 (SB/Direction: Toshifumi Akai, Animation Supervision: Kouno), and he also saw Megumi Kouno's MAD retweeted by Bahi JD.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">- <strong><a href="https://www.sakugabooru.com/post?tags=shingo_yamashita+">Shingo Yamashita</a></strong></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Inoue referred Yama as genius</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">- <a href="https://www.sakugabooru.com/post?tags=bahi_jd+"><strong>Bahi JD</strong></a></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">- <strong><a href="https://www.sakugabooru.com/post?tags=spencer_wan">Spencer Wan</a></strong></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">- <strong><a href="https://www.sakugabooru.com/post?tags=ken%27ichi_fujisawa+">Ken'ichi Fujisawa</a></strong></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Inoue</strong>: "There was amazing guy in One Punch Man and Mob Psycho, and I was wondering who's him/her, but in the end I didn't know the name."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#7eb0e6;"><em><strong>My own works that I'm most proud of</strong></em></span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">- <a href="https://www.sakugabooru.com/post?tags=foxes_of_chironup+">Chironup no Kitsune</a></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Inoue</strong>: "I did around 80 cuts, the storm scene. I was able to replicate <span class="st">Yōichi Kotabe-san's effect, wasn't I?" </span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">- Ghost in the Shell Movie (1995).</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Especially <a href="https://www.sakugabooru.com/post/show/16546">the cut where Major was floating up after diving.</a></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">- Ookami Kodomo to Ame no Yuki (Wolf Children).</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Inoue</strong>: "The scene where the kids were <a href="https://www.sakugabooru.com/post?tags=wolf_children+toshiyuki_inoue+running+-liquid">playing in the snow</a>. I was having fun doing that  flashy cuts."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">- Tobe! Kujira no Peek</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Inoue</strong>: "I was volunteering for the <a href="https://www.sakugabooru.com/post?tags=tobe%21_kujira_no_peek+toshiyuki_inoue+">beginning scene</a>, I'm proud of my sea wave's effect animation. It was right after I saw <a href="https://www.sakugabooru.com/post?tags=gosenzosama_banbanzai+mitsuo_iso+">Mitsuo Iso-san's full limited animation in Gosenzosama Banbanzai!</a> so I was kind of influenced by his animation.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">[About Mitsuo Iso-san's full limited animation]</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Inoue: "Iso-san's full limited technique requires him to draw every drawing in a shot in order to maintain control over the movement, it's quite complicated and I couldn't do it."</p>

<blockquote>[...] Next, in <em>Eva</em> Iso did the beginning of 1 and the end of 19, as well as writing script for the first time, which he has since only done once. His work in 19 is particularly striking and what makes it unique easier to grasp compared with some of his other work. The beastly way the robot moves is closely observed and very convincing in the timing and in the particular actions taken, for example the timing of the way he raises his head and looks around blinking. The close-up shot of the robot biting off a piece of flesh is a classic example of the concept of "full limited" animation that Iso developed, whereby he draws every drawing in a shot in order to maintain control over the movement. Every single drawing contributes to the movement, which jerks dramatically every which way over the screen the way such a shot would undoubtedly look zoomed in with a camera lens from far away.

- <a href="http://www.pelleas.net/aniTOP/index.php/mitsuo_iso">AniPages</a></blockquote>
<p style="text-align:justify;">- Record of Lodoss War OVA Episode 1</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><a href="https://www.sakugabooru.com/post/show/42811">Dragon scene</a> and action.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Inoue</strong>: "During Roujin Z production, Satoshi Kon-san once asked me who did the part where Woodchuck was running and praised it. I was really happy he liked it."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#7eb0e6;"><em><strong>Inoue's Work Schedule</strong></em></span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">13 P.M~: Begins to work.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">17 P.M~: Break, have a dinner and 1 hour walk.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">23 P.M~: Begins to work again.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Inoue</strong>: "I always ensure that I have enough sleep so I only worked around 10 hours a day. Pulling an all nighter is really demanding, and I rarely do this, but sometimes it's fun. During the production of '<span class="st"><em>Evangelion</em>: 3.0 You Can (Not) Redo</span>', I was not in the mood to do every single cut every day, so I piled up the work for some time and pulled all nighter with festive mood."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><em><span style="color:#7eb0e6;"><strong>Current project</strong></span></em></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Inoue: "I'm currently working at Production I.G for an adaptation of novels that won the Japan Booksellers' Award. "</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Honda: "I'm currently working with Hayao Miyazaki-san's on his latest film."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong><em><span style="color:#7eb0e6;">About Takeshi Honda</span></em>
</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Honda</strong>: "When I was doing Nishigokubo with Mahiro Maeda-san, I thought I would just go with animated flipbook style like what I drew in the <a href="https://www.sakugabooru.com/post/show/44755">beginning part</a>. But with that monstrous line up animators, the quality really went up their animation moved seamlessly, I just can't beat it."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Note: In the end Honda drew <a href="https://www.sakugabooru.com/post/show/44761">even more amazing scene</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Full short:</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">https://vimeo.com/149492746</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Inoue</strong>: "Honda-san's animation is probably the ideal style for Japanese Animation. Really stood out but not so jarring."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Honda</strong>: "Well I know the feeling to want to go wild and draw really flashy scene, but thinking from the perspective of animation supervisor, I just can't let out my animation to be so out of place."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Inoue</strong>: "I wonder why Ohira-san is never thinking about how the animation supervisor's felt."</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><em><span style="color:#7eb0e6;"><strong>Talking about character design</strong></span></em></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Honda</strong>: "When I was working with Iso-san in Dennou Coil, the images from character visual I designed and what requested by Iso-san's storyboard were very different. We thought it would be the best to make the characters look cute, but what Iso-san requested were different. He said to me 'isn't protruding chin looks better?', like hell it is!"</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">https://twitter.com/IsoMitsuo/status/1010056594665558017</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">https://twitter.com/IsoMitsuo/status/1010066108353662976</p>

<h6 style="text-align:center;"><em>The initial setting and concept design for Dennou Coil, which were drawn by Takeshi Honda</em></h6>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>Inoue</strong>: "It's not like I want to draw <em>bishoujo</em> characters, but when I asked to draw them I kinda understand the feeling that want to draw them beautifully."</p>]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>46</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2018-08-01 08:24:13</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2018-08-01 08:24:13</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>anime-style-talk-event-notes</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="anime-style"><![CDATA[Anime Style]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="kuso-translation"><![CDATA[kuso translation]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="notes"><![CDATA[Notes]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="takeshi-honda"><![CDATA[Takeshi Honda]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="toshiyuki-inoue"><![CDATA[Toshiyuki Inoue]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="yuuichiro-oguro"><![CDATA[Yuuichiro Oguro]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_3de6be668cb55ab4824d6bfdbf5c68e8</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-twitter"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="ja" dir="ltr">今回はメモ帳のスクショです<br><br>第１４７回アニメスタイルイベント　井上俊之の作画を語ろう<br><br>井上俊之、本田雄、小黒祐一郎 <a href="https://t.co/T2HBpNSffG">pic.twitter.com/T2HBpNSffG</a></p>&mdash; しろみつ (@siromitu) <a href="https://twitter.com/siromitu/status/1013729618900148224?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 2, 2018</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_1da5d107fe198b9d1fabcff1e3cf5c41</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_372a37b3fa07379558ffa678125e44cb</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-vimeo"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/149492746?app_id=122963" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" title="Animator Expo 06 - 20min Walk From Nishi-Ogikubo Station.. No Pets.." webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_372a37b3fa07379558ffa678125e44cb</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1532501938]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_49463b6eb0bda6c8af373348d0b6f574</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-vimeo"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/149492746?app_id=122963" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" title="Animator Expo 06 - 20min Walk From Nishi-Ogikubo Station.. No Pets.." webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_49463b6eb0bda6c8af373348d0b6f574</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1532503939]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_07c59e6722366c988c7da11b61b7465a</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-twitter"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="ja" dir="ltr">というわけで夏に「電脳コイル」の設定資料集「電脳コイルアーカイブス」が出る予定です。とりあえず本田雄’師匠’の未公開ラフからチラ見せ。 <a href="https://t.co/rwiOLOCKrp">pic.twitter.com/rwiOLOCKrp</a></p>&mdash; 磯光雄IsoMitsuo 「地球外少年少女」準備中 (@IsoMitsuo) <a href="https://twitter.com/IsoMitsuo/status/1010056594665558017?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 22, 2018</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_07c59e6722366c988c7da11b61b7465a</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1532504729]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_f2a7c03361d7609205fbf1a51fb02fe6</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-twitter"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="ja" dir="ltr">「電脳コイルアーカイブス」私の初期ラフなんかも載りますが、自分でも未公開かどうかよくわからないものをごった煮で載せる予定です。 <a href="https://t.co/mSh7dc0DHG">pic.twitter.com/mSh7dc0DHG</a></p>&mdash; 磯光雄IsoMitsuo 「地球外少年少女」準備中 (@IsoMitsuo) <a href="https://twitter.com/IsoMitsuo/status/1010066108353662976?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 22, 2018</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_f2a7c03361d7609205fbf1a51fb02fe6</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1532504729]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_da9d039e02fe6aa15570d94a96bb8798</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-vimeo"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/247650360?app_id=122963" width="480" height="360" frameborder="0" title="04 Cream Lemon &#039;85 Pop Chaser" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_da9d039e02fe6aa15570d94a96bb8798</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1532506259]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_d81c05bebc9b1c23e5f3fa45da56efa1</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-vimeo"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/247650360?app_id=122963" width="480" height="360" frameborder="0" title="04 Cream Lemon &#039;85 Pop Chaser" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_d81c05bebc9b1c23e5f3fa45da56efa1</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1532507017]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_502b9cbe42861b7ffe0cfe91ee77aff1</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-twitter"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="ja" dir="ltr">というわけで夏に「電脳コイル」の設定資料集「電脳コイルアーカイブス」が出る予定です。とりあえず本田雄’師匠’の未公開ラフからチラ見せ。 <a href="https://t.co/rwiOLOCKrp">pic.twitter.com/rwiOLOCKrp</a></p>&mdash; 磯光雄IsoMitsuo 「地球外少年少女」準備中 (@IsoMitsuo) <a href="https://twitter.com/IsoMitsuo/status/1010056594665558017?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 22, 2018</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_502b9cbe42861b7ffe0cfe91ee77aff1</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1532507017]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_51a28955336612138295538eaecdf556</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-twitter"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="ja" dir="ltr">「電脳コイルアーカイブス」私の初期ラフなんかも載りますが、自分でも未公開かどうかよくわからないものをごった煮で載せる予定です。 <a href="https://t.co/mSh7dc0DHG">pic.twitter.com/mSh7dc0DHG</a></p>&mdash; 磯光雄IsoMitsuo 「地球外少年少女」準備中 (@IsoMitsuo) <a href="https://twitter.com/IsoMitsuo/status/1010066108353662976?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 22, 2018</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_51a28955336612138295538eaecdf556</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1532507018]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_84b77732600c835bf85f7ef7ab852b72</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_7eceec3a7a0f30ad83995f84333106cd</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_f5d1df3161b05f6bdd57f792d69f5a0f</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_1b5227bb914a4816ea1e3ac5e2e49c78</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_ee950144f4b048b45c178e72d5f9449a</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-twitter"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="ja" dir="ltr">今回はメモ帳のスクショです<br><br>第１４７回アニメスタイルイベント　井上俊之の作画を語ろう<br><br>井上俊之、本田雄、小黒祐一郎 <a href="https://t.co/T2HBpNSffG">pic.twitter.com/T2HBpNSffG</a></p>&mdash; しろみつ (@siromitu) <a href="https://twitter.com/siromitu/status/1013729618900148224?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 2, 2018</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_ee950144f4b048b45c178e72d5f9449a</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1533111855]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_6f8d2ce9236c515908fd1fa254bd9552</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-vimeo"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/247650360?app_id=122963" width="480" height="360" frameborder="0" title="04 Cream Lemon &#039;85 Pop Chaser" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_6f8d2ce9236c515908fd1fa254bd9552</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1533111855]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_f2595f1c3add0c8f6a27b983fc509765</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-vimeo"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/149492746?app_id=122963" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" title="Animator Expo 06 - 20min Walk From Nishi-Ogikubo Station.. No Pets.." webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_f2595f1c3add0c8f6a27b983fc509765</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1533111855]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_076a42e0cbef710e5fb2b79fe7c1a247</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-twitter"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="ja" dir="ltr">というわけで夏に「電脳コイル」の設定資料集「電脳コイルアーカイブス」が出る予定です。とりあえず本田雄’師匠’の未公開ラフからチラ見せ。 <a href="https://t.co/rwiOLOCKrp">pic.twitter.com/rwiOLOCKrp</a></p>&mdash; 磯光雄IsoMitsuo「電脳コイルアーカイブス」夏コミで発売！東７・7923 (@IsoMitsuo) <a href="https://twitter.com/IsoMitsuo/status/1010056594665558017?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 22, 2018</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_076a42e0cbef710e5fb2b79fe7c1a247</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1533111856]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_956834f763c559ad933ba3126ad2741f</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-twitter"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="ja" dir="ltr">「電脳コイルアーカイブス」私の初期ラフなんかも載りますが、自分でも未公開かどうかよくわからないものをごった煮で載せる予定です。 <a href="https://t.co/mSh7dc0DHG">pic.twitter.com/mSh7dc0DHG</a></p>&mdash; 磯光雄IsoMitsuo「電脳コイルアーカイブス」夏コミで発売！東７・7923 (@IsoMitsuo) <a href="https://twitter.com/IsoMitsuo/status/1010066108353662976?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 22, 2018</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_956834f763c559ad933ba3126ad2741f</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1533111856]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[-1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[20614357044]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1533111856]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_f0f2fca0eae6a1991709bbd933ed7689</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_5d31e27a4f91540e5c00fb10e115cb18</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-twitter"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="ja" dir="ltr">今回はメモ帳のスクショです<br><br>第１４７回アニメスタイルイベント　井上俊之の作画を語ろう<br><br>井上俊之、本田雄、小黒祐一郎 <a href="https://t.co/T2HBpNSffG">pic.twitter.com/T2HBpNSffG</a></p>&mdash; しろみつ (@siromitu) <a href="https://twitter.com/siromitu/status/1013729618900148224?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 2, 2018</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_5d31e27a4f91540e5c00fb10e115cb18</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1533111858]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_aaecbe1f1f3220855e7fe688cf3823c2</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-vimeo"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/247650360?app_id=122963" width="480" height="360" frameborder="0" title="04 Cream Lemon &#039;85 Pop Chaser" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_aaecbe1f1f3220855e7fe688cf3823c2</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1533111858]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_e9bfad25ec3370b424ddcac81ed852a8</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-vimeo"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/149492746?app_id=122963" width="584" height="329" frameborder="0" title="Animator Expo 06 - 20min Walk From Nishi-Ogikubo Station.. No Pets.." webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_e9bfad25ec3370b424ddcac81ed852a8</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1533111858]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_4a1fcf41ee7920c606ec6eea44f6953c</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-twitter"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="ja" dir="ltr">というわけで夏に「電脳コイル」の設定資料集「電脳コイルアーカイブス」が出る予定です。とりあえず本田雄’師匠’の未公開ラフからチラ見せ。 <a href="https://t.co/rwiOLOCKrp">pic.twitter.com/rwiOLOCKrp</a></p>&mdash; 磯光雄IsoMitsuo「電脳コイルアーカイブス」夏コミで発売！東７・7923 (@IsoMitsuo) <a href="https://twitter.com/IsoMitsuo/status/1010056594665558017?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 22, 2018</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_4a1fcf41ee7920c606ec6eea44f6953c</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1533111858]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_7350765c77e09d50804292a596e8b0c4</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-twitter"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="ja" dir="ltr">「電脳コイルアーカイブス」私の初期ラフなんかも載りますが、自分でも未公開かどうかよくわからないものをごった煮で載せる予定です。 <a href="https://t.co/mSh7dc0DHG">pic.twitter.com/mSh7dc0DHG</a></p>&mdash; 磯光雄IsoMitsuo「電脳コイルアーカイブス」夏コミで発売！東７・7923 (@IsoMitsuo) <a href="https://twitter.com/IsoMitsuo/status/1010066108353662976?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 22, 2018</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_7350765c77e09d50804292a596e8b0c4</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1533111859]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_0b7b6b3e3cba88bd3dabdfeb392fcedb</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-twitter"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="ja" dir="ltr">今回はメモ帳のスクショです<br><br>第１４７回アニメスタイルイベント　井上俊之の作画を語ろう<br><br>井上俊之、本田雄、小黒祐一郎 <a href="https://t.co/T2HBpNSffG">pic.twitter.com/T2HBpNSffG</a></p>&mdash; しろみつ (@siromitu) <a href="https://twitter.com/siromitu/status/1013729618900148224?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 2, 2018</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_0b7b6b3e3cba88bd3dabdfeb392fcedb</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1533111860]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_2f9af9e9e2302835e23ba391d1f07b34</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-twitter"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="ja" dir="ltr">今回はメモ帳のスクショです<br><br>第１４７回アニメスタイルイベント　井上俊之の作画を語ろう<br><br>井上俊之、本田雄、小黒祐一郎 <a href="https://t.co/T2HBpNSffG">pic.twitter.com/T2HBpNSffG</a></p>&mdash; しろみつ (@siromitu) <a href="https://twitter.com/siromitu/status/1013729618900148224?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 2, 2018</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_2f9af9e9e2302835e23ba391d1f07b34</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1533111952]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_5592e559c2624979d73e7a13d0955449</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_0b61cd9915866cbd47cfe07714c077a9</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-vimeo"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/247650360?app_id=122963" width="480" height="360" frameborder="0" title="04 Cream Lemon &#039;85 Pop Chaser" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_0b61cd9915866cbd47cfe07714c077a9</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1541665975]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_75ece2ea5bd72d123d22d415e96dcdc5</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_7a6fcb0c1e584cd1780057a47690f5ef</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-vimeo"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/149492746?app_id=122963" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" title="Animator Expo 06 - 20min Walk From Nishi-Ogikubo Station.. No Pets.." allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_7a6fcb0c1e584cd1780057a47690f5ef</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1541665976]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_f1abc46a7711cb036c13e8e4a26df17a</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-twitter"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="ja" dir="ltr">というわけで夏に「電脳コイル」の設定資料集「電脳コイルアーカイブス」が出る予定です。とりあえず本田雄’師匠’の未公開ラフからチラ見せ。 <a href="https://t.co/rwiOLOCKrp">pic.twitter.com/rwiOLOCKrp</a></p>&mdash; 磯光雄IsoMitsuo「電脳コイルアーカイブス」発売中！ (@IsoMitsuo) <a href="https://twitter.com/IsoMitsuo/status/1010056594665558017?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 22, 2018</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_3de6be668cb55ab4824d6bfdbf5c68e8</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1541665974]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_f1abc46a7711cb036c13e8e4a26df17a</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1541665976]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_5c9b6e5234ebd4e75f5380542a9e66b0</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-twitter"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="ja" dir="ltr">「電脳コイルアーカイブス」私の初期ラフなんかも載りますが、自分でも未公開かどうかよくわからないものをごった煮で載せる予定です。 <a href="https://t.co/mSh7dc0DHG">pic.twitter.com/mSh7dc0DHG</a></p>&mdash; 磯光雄IsoMitsuo「電脳コイルアーカイブス」発売中！ (@IsoMitsuo) <a href="https://twitter.com/IsoMitsuo/status/1010066108353662976?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 22, 2018</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_5c9b6e5234ebd4e75f5380542a9e66b0</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1541665976]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_5754e661ac808a6170bcb103e185842e</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:comment>
    <wp:comment_id>4</wp:comment_id>
    <wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Rukawa]]></wp:comment_author>
    <wp:comment_author_email>rukawa@ecchi.fr</wp:comment_author_email>
    <wp:comment_author_url>http://www.manganimation.net</wp:comment_author_url>
    <wp:comment_author_IP>37.168.63.67</wp:comment_author_IP>
    <wp:comment_date>2018-08-09 18:18:54</wp:comment_date>
    <wp:comment_date_gmt>2018-08-09 18:18:54</wp:comment_date_gmt>
    <wp:comment_content><![CDATA[ok so i just learnt that the "full limited animation" was a term invented by Ben Ettinger, japaneses just call it "subete genga"]]></wp:comment_content>
    <wp:comment_approved>0</wp:comment_approved>
    <wp:comment_type/>
    <wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
    <wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>false</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>a:3:{s:4:"time";d:1533838735.157827;s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:6:"awakur";}</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>a:3:{s:4:"time";d:1533843887.597043;s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:6:"awakur";}</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
  </wp:comment>
  <wp:comment>
    <wp:comment_id>8</wp:comment_id>
    <wp:comment_author><![CDATA[What&#8217;s The Most Popular Japanese Animation? &#8211; Sakuga Blog]]></wp:comment_author>
    <wp:comment_author_email/>
    <wp:comment_author_url>https://blog.sakugabooru.com/2018/08/16/whats-the-most-popular-japanese-animation/</wp:comment_author_url>
    <wp:comment_author_IP>104.152.185.138</wp:comment_author_IP>
    <wp:comment_date>2018-08-16 17:56:57</wp:comment_date>
    <wp:comment_date_gmt>2018-08-16 17:56:57</wp:comment_date_gmt>
    <wp:comment_content><![CDATA[[&#8230;] alike being attracted to them. Takeshi Honda, popularly known as the Master of Japanese animation, recently expressed his worries that many young animators nowadays try to mirror Yutaka Nakamura&amp;rsqu&#8230; animation without first grasping the fundamentals. Taking it out of context that might sound [&#8230;]]]></wp:comment_content>
    <wp:comment_approved>0</wp:comment_approved>
    <wp:comment_type>pingback</wp:comment_type>
    <wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
    <wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>false</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>a:2:{s:4:"time";d:1534442217.711128;s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";}</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>a:2:{s:4:"time";d:1534446156.437385;s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";}</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
  </wp:comment>
  <wp:comment>
    <wp:comment_id>9</wp:comment_id>
    <wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Anon]]></wp:comment_author>
    <wp:comment_author_email>123fakestreet@aol.com</wp:comment_author_email>
    <wp:comment_author_url/>
    <wp:comment_author_IP>108.44.195.45</wp:comment_author_IP>
    <wp:comment_date>2018-08-17 15:06:33</wp:comment_date>
    <wp:comment_date_gmt>2018-08-17 15:06:33</wp:comment_date_gmt>
    <wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Hey, I just wanted to say that this translation is very much appreciated!]]></wp:comment_content>
    <wp:comment_approved>0</wp:comment_approved>
    <wp:comment_type/>
    <wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
    <wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>false</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>a:2:{s:4:"time";d:1534518394.470129;s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";}</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>a:2:{s:4:"time";d:1534522090.466073;s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";}</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
  </wp:comment>
</item>
<item>
  <title>anime style memo 21st july</title>
  <link>https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/?p=62</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov -0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>kyuudere</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/?p=62</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[21st july notes

アニスタイベントメモ
井上:
正直カリスマはやめて欲しいんだよね笑
最近言う機会多いけど、中村豊さんみたいな華のある人が呼ばれるべきではないですかね。

Inoue:
Honestly, I want people to stop calling me charisma (laughs). Recently I've had the chances to say this, but I don't have the right to be after all.
アニスタイベントメモ
小黒:
最近井上ブーム来てますよ。
原画集も凄く売れてますしね。
本田:
井上ブーム？それよく分からないんだよね。それを言ってしまえば俺は高校生からずっと井上俊之ブームだよ。

Oguro: "Recently there's Charisma boom. Your genga book sell pretty well. "

Honda: "Inoue boom? I don't quite understand it. If you said there's Inoue boom, then I have been in Inoue boom since I was in high school."

#さよ朝 アニスタイベントメモ
井上:
100カット担当出来ないカットがどうしても出来てしまう事が分かった。その出来ない分のカットなどは師匠などに直接連絡してお願いした。本当は自分でやりたかったが、自分の望むクオリティで上げてくれる人は限られているので師匠などにお願いした。

[Topic: Maquia]

Inoue: "During the production of Maquia I had 100 cuts that weren't completed, and I knew very well I couldn't finish it in time. So I had an idea to contact some people I knew like Honda-san. Actually I wanted to finish it by myself, but I had to compromise with the help of people that I'm sure of they will be able to deliver with the quality I'd wanted."

#さよ朝 アニスタイベントメモ
井上:
ラフで終わった絵もあるし、今回の仕事(絵)はそこまで緻密とは思っていない。
本田:
緻密ですよ。コスチュームとか特殊で手間はかなりかかった。設定見た時シンプルだったから騙された。

Inoue: "Well, there are some cuts that ended up fine just with rough drawings, I don't think this production demands such a very minute detail."

Honda: "Wait, it does. Drawing the costume already took much time for me. I was fooled because the <em>settei</em> Inoue-san showed to me looked simple."

#さよ朝 アニスタイベントメモ
小黒:
こんなに(1本の作品？)で働いた人はいませんよ。
井上:
20代の方が働いていた。でも、見終わった後は珍しく満足出来たしもうすぐ死ぬんじゃないかな。

Ogura: I think no one has worked this much for a single movie like you. (Surprised)

Inoue: No, actually when I was in my 20s I worked much harder than this. Even so, when I finished watching the (complete) movie, somehow I was satisfied with it, that's pretty rare for me to felt that way. I wonder if I've been getting old and my end is near.

&nbsp;

アニスタイベントメモ
MEMORIES
井上:
作監をやりたくないとゴネていたけどPの田中栄子さんに口説かれる形で参加した。手のかからない人材を集めて修正を最小限に抑えると言われたのを信じたが結局は6割程描き直した。

[MEMORIES]

Inoue: "Actually I'd clearly refused the job (as animation supervisor), but the producer Eiko Tanaka-san finally persuaded me by saying she would assemble a team consisted of talented people to minimize the correction that would be needed. But in the end I corrected around 60% of it."

Inoue:

アニスタイベントメモ
MEMORIES
井上:
当時は自信満々に描いていた気がする。技術的にも迷いがなかったし確認手段も少なかったので殆ど勘で描いていた。

At the time I felt like I was drawing it with so much confidence. There were no many

アニスタイベントメモ
井上:
原画を前に置かれると違いが気になり直してしまう。
沖浦:
井上さんはシートの書き間違えをする。それは自分が直したりした。

Inoue: I once made a mistake when <em>, </em>someone else noticed it and fixed it.

Okiura: Inoue-san drew on the wrong sheet, and I was the one who fixed it.

沖浦:
回想シーンはやりたい事を詰め込み過ぎてことごとく失敗してしまった。バラのシーンは頑張った。

I tried to stuffed so much things in that recollection scene, and it accidentally became a blunder. I particularly put so much effort on the rose scene.

アニスタイベントメモ
MEMORIES
本田:
パトレイバーなどに参加している人達はあっちの人という認識で羨ましいと思っていた。1カットだけNCで参加。
井上:
中山勝一さんのカットが妙にうまいと思って制作に聞いたら師匠が参加している事を知った。

Honda: I envied the Patlabor crew because

アニスタイベントメモ
MEMORIES
井上:
師匠の担当パートを知っている人は極僅かなはず。
小黒:
作画wikiに書いてありましたよ。
井上:
！？！？

アニスタイベントメモ
沖浦:
AKIRAの時に自分とうつのみやさんで「10カット中1カットだけでもうまくできたら良いかなぁ」と話していたら井上さんが「俺は全部のカットを良くしたい」と言っていた。
井上:
そんな事言った覚えがない。

Okiura: At the time of AKIRA, I remember I was talking with Utsunomiya-san something like "It'd be good if at least I could draw good 1 cut out of 10 cuts..." and then Inoue-san said "I'd rather want all my cuts turn out to be good".

Inoue: I don't remember saying something like that.

アニスタイベントメモ
MEMORIES
沖浦:
当時、動きの中でわざと間を抜いたりしてたけど井上さんのブームだったのでは？
井上:
磯君の御先祖様を見てから意図的に原画でメリハリをコントロールするようになった。

MEMORIES

Okiura: At the time of Memories, you did remove the  in the movement (of your animation), was that also Inoue-boom?

Inoue: I figured it out after watching Iso-kun's Gosenzosama Banbanzai and I did it on purpose to sharply control the movement.

*Note: Most likely Inoue was using the Iso's full-limited technique, in which the gap between each of the key animation should be shortened.

アニスタイベントメモ
MEMORIES
小黒:
湯浅さんが洋画を見ているようだと絶賛していた。
井上:
それは嬉しい。実際にブレードランナーのハリソン・フォードの様な洋画っぽい実在する人間っぽさを意識した。

&nbsp;

アニスタイベントメモ
小黒:
鬼太郎の磯君は井上さんリスペクトですよね。
井上:
当時はうまいやついるなぁと思った。タイミングとか自分に似ていてちょっと嬉しかった。

Ogura: Iso's Gegege no Kiitaro was a respect letter for Inoue right.

Inoue: When he first appeared, I thought to myself "now this man is the real deal". I was a bit happy that he had similar timing to my animation.

アニスタイベントメモ
本田さんについて
井上:
ナディアの1話から凄い人来たなと思っていた。
本田:
20代の仕事は殆どトラウマ。もがき苦しんでいた時期だった。「井上さん、大平さんならどう描くか？」を常に意識したり。とにかく形から入っていた。

Topic: Takeshi Honda

Inoue: When Nadia's first episode aired, I thought "finally an amazing animator has appeared".

Honda: It was

アニスタイベントメモ
人狼
井上:
最初は作監振られた。
沖浦:
飲み屋に誘って自分のラフスケッチを見せて井上さんにやってもらおうとした。
井上:
MEMORIESで作監が出来たのは4℃だった事もあって、I.Gでは出来ないと思った。まずキャラデザが嫌い。

アニスタイベントメモ
人狼:作監について
作監について
沖浦:
他に誰か良い人はいないかと探していたら、候補に吉原くんの上手い友達と八犬伝の上手い人が上がって偶然何方も西尾さんだった。

アニスタイベントメモ
人狼:作監について
井上:
沖浦の横で作監をするのはとても大変だった。技術的についていけないといけない上に精神もタフじゃないと務まらない。西尾はアホみたいに図太かった(実際は乙女)から務まった。

アニスタイベントメモ
人狼:レイアウトチェックについて
井上:
沖浦や今敏さんなどがいたからレイアウトは苦手意識があった。当時は人狼に対応出来るレイアウトを描ける人が殆どいなかったので俺がやるしかないなと。

アニスタイベントメモ
人狼
沖浦:
自分の代わりの事を井上さんにやって貰った。簡単な口頭指示でやり取り出来る関係。他の人には説明しなければならない事もお互いの意図を汲み取る事が出来るので簡潔な指示で伝わる。

アニスタイベントメモ
本田:
ももへの手紙で分厚い原画の修正が来たけど何も指示が書いてなくて何をすれば良いか分からなかった。
クイックアクションレコーダーで実際に見て自己判断するしかなかった。
井上:
師匠の仕事は常にプロフェッショナルだよ。

アニスタイベントメモ
本田:
当時(20代後半)は目の大きい女の子ばかり描いていてうんざりしていたので影なしで写実的なデザインにビビッときた。これをやりたい。エヴァみたいなアニメな絵を描きたくない時期。
井上:
当時は線を増やしてディテールアップさせたり情報量を増やした濃い絵が主流だった。

アニスタイベントメモ
井上:
師匠デザインの千年女優はアウトラインのとり方が人狼っぽかった。動きの表現を求めている人にとってはディテールの多い絵は邪魔だと感じるはず。
沖浦:
人狼はプロテクトギアの中で人が動いている事を表現するだけでも大変だった。]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>62</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2019-02-25 06:02:50</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name/>
  <wp:status>draft</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
</item>
<item>
  <title>talk event</title>
  <link>https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/2018/08/01/anime-style-talk-event-notes/talk-event/</link>
  <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 07:31:52 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>kyuudere</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://sakyuuga.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/talk-event.jpg</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>63</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2018-07-31 07:31:52</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2018-07-31 07:31:52</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>closed</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>talk-event</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>46</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://sakyuuga.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/talk-event.jpg</wp:attachment_url>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Tadashi Hiramatsu's Camerawork Lesson</title>
  <link>https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/2018/08/08/tadashi-hiramatsus-camerawork-lesson/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 09:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>kyuudere</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/?p=70</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:justify;">Hi, this is a small post that I just want to share because it's kinda interesting. The original post was from Tadashi Hiramatsu's blog, which focused on camerawork definition, especially PAN and FOLLOW. Those are terms that often used by fans and people anime or live action film industries. You must've found those terms in  anime storyboards too, such as this one (Source: Ohayou's storyboard by Satoshi Kon).</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-87" src="https://sakyuuga.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/1a253285f6e55d5826c3dec7e1b16edb1-e1533107321357.jpg" alt="1a253285f6e55d5826c3dec7e1b16edb1.jpg" width="978" height="596" /></span></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">このカットもわずかにPAN.←を加えます。TL: Add a slight PAN for this cut [004] too.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">This is only a translation of what Hiramatsu has written on his blog, as I didn't do any research for this post aside from few examples that I might give.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">There's also few parts that I omitted from the original blog post, such as the talk about economy. It's simply because I lack the understanding of many complicated economic terms, and it's not that relevant with the technical points of this post.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Anyway, you can read the original blog post here:</p>
https://ameblo.jp/tadashi-hiramatz/entry-12380474324.html

<span style="color:#333300;">====</span>

<span style="text-decoration:underline;">Tadashi Hiramatsu blog starts from here:</span>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Finally, 'Sayonara no Asa ni Yakusoku Hana wo Kazarou: Inoue Toshiyuki's genga book' has been released this month. For those who purchased the limited edition, there's a bonus video, a three-man talk between Inoue-san, Horikawa-san, and me. I heard the sample can be accessed on YouTube too.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">https://youtu.be/ouPZlAadqf4</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Please look forward to our discussion and buy the book....but before that, let me write a supplementary lesson about  the meaning of 'camerawork technique' which often came out in our discussion.</p>
It's about PAN.
<p style="text-align:justify;">What is the difference between PAN, Follow PAN, つけPAN? Such a question is frequently asked on twitter right? Actually the confusion lies when you're thinking camerawork on paper.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">First, let's check the meaning of the word itself.</p>
PAN is an abbreviation of Panorama.

Follow means "to follow [an object]".
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#eda1a1;">PAN</span> is a camerawork technique where you place a camera on <span style="color:#eda1a1;">f</span><span style="color:#333300;"><span style="color:#eda1a1;">ixed position</span></span>, and you try to chase a moving [photographic] subject to keep it in camera's frame, by moving the camera left and right. Such a  technique to show a landscape, or large objects such as a ship, an airplane, or even a <em>kaijuu</em> can be called PAN too.<span style="color:#333300;">
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">In Japanese animation, even fixed camera moved up and down called as PAN UP /DOWN, but the original term is TILT UP/DOWN. As you can guess, term came from the word "tilt". Well, it's okay to use term PAN UP/DOWN too.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">And as I'd highlighted in previous paragraph , the important part about PAN is the camera is placed in <span style="color:#eda1a1;">fixed position</span>, and it is moved right and left to follow moving object.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#eda1a1;">Follow </span>is a camerawork technique where you <span style="color:#eda1a1;">move a camera </span>accordingly to a moving [photographic] subject that you want to capture within camera's frame.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">However, you need to be careful here. Since <span style="color:#f7b0b0;">Follow </span>means to move a camera according to a moving subject, it does not include the meaning of whether the camera is fixed or not. So, PAN is also falling under this definition. Hence appears a term 'Follow PAN', which becomes the source of confusion.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">To clarify the meaning, I think it's better to use the term <span style="color:#eda1a1;">Dolly</span>.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">As you can guess, the term came from word "dolly", a platform on a roller or on wheels or casters for moving heavy objects.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">In short, it is a shooting technique where you put a camera on a dolly, and then move it while chasing a moving photographic subject.</p>

<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#7abff0;">Note</span>:
A famous example of Dolly/Follow camerawork is Makoto's running scene in <em>Toki wo Kakeru Shoujo</em>, which directed by Mamoru Hosoda and the scene was animated by Ryo Timo (Ryosuke Sawa). You can see Hosoda's storyboard <a href="https://www.sakugabooru.com/post/show/30657">here</a>, where he gave 'Follow' instruction.</p>
&nbsp;
<p style="text-align:center;">https://youtu.be/DKSeC13MsdA</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">As you can see, the Dolly/Follow camerawork is easy to understand here. It gives the impression that the audience was following Makoto while holding a camera to film her running figure. She was struggling to follow camera's pace at first, but then she gradually put more strength and finally was able to outrun the camera.</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align:justify;">There is also another method like using a crane, you can put a camera on a crane and move it up and down, left and right. You can also combine it with PAN to make a complex footage, I like this and there are several shots created using this method in SayoAsa.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">So, what important is the definition whether the camera is fixed, or moved. I think the distinction between 'PAN' and 'Dolly' or 'move' makes it easier to imagine the difference between 'fixed camera' and 'moving camera'.</p>
Then, do you understand what I mean by confusion when you're thinking on paper?
<p style="text-align:justify;">Since camerawork in anime is applied from live-action shooting techniques, it would be confusing if we haven't  fully grasped the relation between the subject and camera in real space.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I often study old movies such as Hitchcock's works because there is no technology such as CG, and because at the time the camera is still large and inconvenient it makes me easier to understand the mechanism of live action's camerawork techniques.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Recent live action movies are not much different from anime in the aspect of filming techniques, so I think they are not suitable examples to learn about filming fundamentals.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Basically, you need to be aware that the camera is "cutting off" the real space.</p>
If it's hard to understand through words, let me show it through images. I'm sorry it's a bit rough since they're only impromptu sketches that I made.

First is 'PAN'.
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class=" size-full wp-image-123 aligncenter" src="https://sakyuuga.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/pan.jpg" alt="PAN" width="800" height="361" /></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">In the case of PAN, the angle of view (the angle between camera and photographic subject) changes because the camera is in fixed position. I draw the image with a bit of exaggeration but the point is, when you film a moving photographic subject (from a fixed position) that comes from left, as you rotate the camera to follow the subject that moves to the right side, the image of subject and the background are changing because you took it from varying angles.</p>
And here is the case for 'Dolly'.

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-124" src="https://sakyuuga.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/dolly.jpg" alt="Dolly" width="800" height="361" />
<p style="text-align:justify;">The direction of the background's streamlines are reversed ^_^; ....well, putting that aside, do you understand my point?</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">The angle of the moving photographic subject and the background are not changing because you film it on a dolly as you follow the subject.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">When I use 'Follow' in my storyboards, I write it 'Follow (moving)'. 'Dolly' is not a general term so it's not widely used yet, but I think it may be good if we could switch to it in the future.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">To fully understand the two, you must not glued to your desk. Go outside and observe it with your own eyes.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Walk outside, and try to stop at the sidewalk and observe a moving car. That is 'PAN'.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Take a train or bus, then observe the moving cars and vehicles from side window, that is 'Dolly'. (Don't try it while driving car or bicycle since it's dangerous!)</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">When I'm animating or directing, rather than watching film (live action or animation), my first priority is to observe real people, things, and landscapes.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">It is unexpectedly difficult to read the author's intentions from their work. This is because it's easier to be aware of what you have seen with your own eyes rather than what other people have intended you to see.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">If you look at the work after observing it with your own eyes, I think you can grasp the author's intentions more adequately.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">First you need to make a clear picture of what you want to create, and choose the method that you wish to clear what you've aimed at.</p>
...Choose the right method to clear what you have aimed at.

&nbsp;
<p style="text-align:justify;">Well, now. What is 'つけPAN'? (read: tsuke-PAN)</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">This is not a general term in camerawork techniques, but a technical term exclusive to anime. 'つけPAN' can be used in the case of 'PAN' or 'Dolly' in anime.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">In Japanese animation, a cell of subject or object moves at 2s or 3s, but filming (撮影) moves at 1s.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">When you chase a photographic subject with PAN, but the subject/object moves in 2s or 3s while the background moves in 1s, a gap will appears and you'll find the images on screen rattling or vibrating.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Let me give you an easy to understand example. In the second half of 'Lupin III: the Castle of Cagliostro', the scene where the autogyro was hovering over the north castle looked a bit rattled on screen.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">(<span style="color:#7abff0;">Note</span>: It seems the referred cut is <a href="https://www.sakugabooru.com/post/show/37520">this one</a>, starts from 0:23 onward?)</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">It's also the case when you see the characters walking on the ground, there appears a gap between the characters and ground which resulted in such a rattling effect.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">(<span style="color:#7abff0;">Note</span>: I'm not sure about this one, but to give another example it may be best to observe <a href="https://www.sakugabooru.com/post/show/37519">this cut</a>, the scene where Lupin and Zenigata were trying to escape from people who were chasing them. From 0:22 ~ 0:23, there's a slight PAN that has been used in that shot, and the way they run looked out of sync when the camera is doing PAN.)</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">To prevent this, we use a tap (camera's shooting axis) that secures the cell (such as characters) and film it separately from the background. This is an analog method, but the principle is same even for digital era.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">With this, the camera's filming at the same pace as the cell, even if the animation moves in 3s, there will be no rattling effects appear on screen.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">However, when it is combined with background, it still does appear to be rattling.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Hence you can't use つけPAN when there's a combination of characters movement and moving background (in the case that the characters' movement is in 2s or 3s).</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">The solution is, characters should move in 1s too.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I'll use 'Lupin III: the Fuma Conspiracy' as an example. In the second half, the cut where the camera follows Lupin and co. who entered the cave from left to right, was made in 1s.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I could tell it because the animation suddenly moves in full animation (1s).</p>
&nbsp;

&nbsp;

That's it.
<p style="text-align:justify;">'PAN', and 'Dolly' or 'Follow (move)' are camerawork's terms.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">It's alright to comprehend 'つけPAN' as an anime technique's term.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">So, it's kind of wrong to give instruction such as "use 'つけPAN'", it's more correct if it's written like this: "In this PAN, use 'つけPAN'". In other words, it's like saying "In this camerawork, use this technique.", which is more thorough.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I think the usage of camerawork in digital animation &amp; filming has changed, but the basic stays the same.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I often say this in '<em>sakuga uchiawase</em>' : "Try it (moving) yourself to grasp how it should move". But it's also applicable when you're thinking about camerawork, don't think on paper, test it yourself by holding a camera and observe how the footage looked like when you moved the camera. I recommend this way to fully grasp camerawork.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Such a way would surely enrich the image, wouldn't it?</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Although anime has its own uniqueness in animation and camerawork, but animation is originally a video expression so I think it's better if you know the basic of live action filming and apply it in animation.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">To sum it up, everything is from the basic first.</p>
&nbsp;
<p style="text-align:justify;">Inoue-san drawings have such a clear consciousness of that "real space between camera and subject" too.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Looking at Inoue-san's genga book or going to see his genga exhibition at Sasayuri Cafe might've made you thinking: "Hmm...so it's like that, I understand everything now."</p>]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>70</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2018-08-08 09:01:34</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2018-08-08 09:01:34</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>tadashi-hiramatsus-camerawork-lesson</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="camerawork"><![CDATA[camerawork]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="kuso-translation"><![CDATA[kuso translation]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="tadashi-hiramatsu"><![CDATA[Tadashi Hiramatsu]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_bfcd1b8b0286e04f7fd17734c6956c6d</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_bfcd1b8b0286e04f7fd17734c6956c6d</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_afc15abb10715bf03ab78d0808ec1251</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_b28bcaf3d0fe261bc0a08ab966c22793</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1533718897]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[-1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[20857439461]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_44c68b80d83f4c3da18769a90a975905</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_2f9af9e9e2302835e23ba391d1f07b34</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-twitter"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="ja" dir="ltr">今回はメモ帳のスクショです<br><br>第１４７回アニメスタイルイベント　井上俊之の作画を語ろう<br><br>井上俊之、本田雄、小黒祐一郎 <a href="https://t.co/T2HBpNSffG">pic.twitter.com/T2HBpNSffG</a></p>&mdash; しろみつ (@siromitu) <a href="https://twitter.com/siromitu/status/1013729618900148224?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 2, 2018</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_2f9af9e9e2302835e23ba391d1f07b34</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1533734041]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:comment>
    <wp:comment_id>12</wp:comment_id>
    <wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Arilando]]></wp:comment_author>
    <wp:comment_author_email>japanese.revleft@gmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
    <wp:comment_author_url/>
    <wp:comment_author_IP>86.52.104.19</wp:comment_author_IP>
    <wp:comment_date>2018-11-27 17:49:21</wp:comment_date>
    <wp:comment_date_gmt>2018-11-27 17:49:21</wp:comment_date_gmt>
    <wp:comment_content><![CDATA[&gt;For those who purchased the limited edition, there’s a bonus video, a three-man talk between Inoue-san, Horikawa-san, and me. I heard the sample can be accessed on YouTube too.
Why were you a part of that talk? Are you an important person? I thought you were just some random guy on twitter.]]></wp:comment_content>
    <wp:comment_approved>0</wp:comment_approved>
    <wp:comment_type/>
    <wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
    <wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>a:2:{s:4:"time";d:1543345633.873858;s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";}</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>false</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>a:2:{s:4:"time";d:1543340962.877691;s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";}</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
  </wp:comment>
  <wp:comment>
    <wp:comment_id>13</wp:comment_id>
    <wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Arilando]]></wp:comment_author>
    <wp:comment_author_email>japanese.revleft@gmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
    <wp:comment_author_url/>
    <wp:comment_author_IP>86.52.104.19</wp:comment_author_IP>
    <wp:comment_date>2018-11-27 17:54:26</wp:comment_date>
    <wp:comment_date_gmt>2018-11-27 17:54:26</wp:comment_date_gmt>
    <wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Please don't approve that comment (or this one). I misunderstood something, sorry.]]></wp:comment_content>
    <wp:comment_approved>0</wp:comment_approved>
    <wp:comment_type/>
    <wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
    <wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>a:2:{s:4:"time";d:1543345634.266552;s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";}</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>a:2:{s:4:"time";d:1543341268.063717;s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";}</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>false</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
  </wp:comment>
</item>
<item>
  <title>1a253285f6e55d5826c3dec7e1b16edb</title>
  <link>https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/2018/08/08/tadashi-hiramatsus-camerawork-lesson/1a253285f6e55d5826c3dec7e1b16edb-2/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 07:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>kyuudere</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://sakyuuga.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/1a253285f6e55d5826c3dec7e1b16edb1.jpg</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>87</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2018-08-01 07:07:52</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2018-08-01 07:07:52</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>closed</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>1a253285f6e55d5826c3dec7e1b16edb-2</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>70</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://sakyuuga.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/1a253285f6e55d5826c3dec7e1b16edb1-e1533107321357.jpg</wp:attachment_url>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wp_original_post_media</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[O:8:"stdClass":6:{s:4:"date";s:25:"2018-08-01T07:07:52+00:00";s:3:"URL";s:82:"https://sakyuuga.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/1a253285f6e55d5826c3dec7e1b16edb1.jpg";s:4:"file";s:37:"1a253285f6e55d5826c3dec7e1b16edb1.jpg";s:9:"extension";s:3:"jpg";s:9:"mime_type";s:10:"image/jpeg";s:4:"size";i:309245;}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>410547cdcec087d283b4a888d02426c4</title>
  <link>https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/2018/08/08/tadashi-hiramatsus-camerawork-lesson/410547cdcec087d283b4a888d02426c4/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 05:06:34 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>kyuudere</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://sakyuuga.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/410547cdcec087d283b4a888d02426c4.jpg</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>122</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2018-08-08 05:06:34</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2018-08-08 05:06:34</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>closed</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>410547cdcec087d283b4a888d02426c4</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>70</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://sakyuuga.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/410547cdcec087d283b4a888d02426c4.jpg</wp:attachment_url>
</item>
<item>
  <title>PAN</title>
  <link>https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/2018/08/08/tadashi-hiramatsus-camerawork-lesson/pan/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 06:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>kyuudere</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://sakyuuga.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/pan.jpg</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>123</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2018-08-08 06:10:20</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2018-08-08 06:10:20</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>closed</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>pan</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>70</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://sakyuuga.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/pan.jpg</wp:attachment_url>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Dolly</title>
  <link>https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/2018/08/08/tadashi-hiramatsus-camerawork-lesson/dolly/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 06:21:35 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>kyuudere</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://sakyuuga.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/dolly.jpg</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>124</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2018-08-08 06:21:35</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2018-08-08 06:21:35</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>closed</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>dolly</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>70</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://sakyuuga.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/dolly.jpg</wp:attachment_url>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Animators' round-table discussion: The Working Environtment is Not Improving, But New Talents Keep Growing?</title>
  <link>https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/?p=132</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov -0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>kyuudere</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/?p=132</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:justify;">First, let me write a few things. This is only a rough translation of a recently published interview or round-table discussion with three young <em>enshutsu</em> by popular culture digital media website, KAI-YOU. I'd suggest you to visit the original article at their website too:</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">http://kai-you.net/article/56347</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">The translation is not perfect as I'm still learning English and Japanese, but I hope the messages get across to you readers. If you happen to notice some grammatical/translation errors or typos in this article, I'd like to apologize first. I'd be more than glad to accept some corrections from readers, as it would certainly help me to improve my articles. I'll try to revise my blog posts if I have the time.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">====</p>

<h2><strong>Even though the the working environment is not improving, new talents keep growing? </strong></h2>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Anime industry is growing into a big business which is said to have market scale more than 2 Trillion Yen. (Data taken from The Anime Industry Report of 2017, published by The Association of Japanese Animations which can be downloaded <a href="http://aja.gr.jp/?wpdmdl=1155">here</a>.)</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">But on the other hand, the occupational stress suffered by the staff is large, such a harsh working environment like long working time and low wages also have often been pointed out (by media).*</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Here we have invited three energetic young creators who arrived from anime production side, and we will listen to their stories such as <strong>the tips to earn a living as an animator,</strong> <strong>the influence of on demand broadcast to working environment</strong>, and <strong>circumstance like overseas outsourcing.</strong>  Also we will hear their honest opinions on current situation surrounding their working environment and the future of it.</p>
First, we will introduce our guest speakers.
<blockquote>
<h4 class="yellow">Keisuke Kojima (小嶋慶祐)</h4>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img style="max-width:100%;" src="https://kai-you.net/press/img/reMmA_Vcld_400x400.jpg" /></p>
<strong>Work experiences: Key Animation, Key Animation Supervision, Storyboard Artist, Enshutsu</strong>

Born in 1991 in Niigata Prefecture.  At the age of eighteen he moved to Tokyo and worked at Gainax, and currently belong to Revoroot which was founded in 2016. When he was in high school he made an indie animation "エアーマンが倒せない" which he submitted to nico nico douga and became a huge hit. He has a wide work experience and has worked in anime such as 'Zettai Karen Children', 'Yuyushiki', 'One-Punch Man', and 'ACCA: 13-ku Kansatsu-ka".

Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/kkeisuke220">@kkeisuke220</a></blockquote>
&nbsp;
<blockquote><strong>Kazuto Arai (</strong><strong>荒井和人)</strong>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img style="max-width:100%;" src="https://kai-you.net/press/img/resTmcdz0Z_400x400.jpg" /></p>
<strong>Work experiences: Key Animation, Storyboard Artist, Enshutsu</strong>

Born in 1991 in Tokyo. Famous with his twitter handle 'Barikios'

Graduated from Tokyo Institute of Technology. After working at TRIGGER, he started working as as freelance animator and director (演出家). He has worked in anime such as 'Senki Zesshou Symphogear ZX', 'Mob Psycho 100', 'Re:CREATORS', and 'FLCL Progressive'.

Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/Barikios">@Barikios</a></blockquote>
&nbsp;
<blockquote><strong>Makoto Nakazono (</strong><strong>中園真登)</strong>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img style="max-width:100%;" src="https://kai-you.net/press/img/reRBC4Ucd0_400x400.jpg" /></p>
<strong>Work experiences: Enshutsu, Storyboard Artist*</strong>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Born in 1988 in Tokyo. Graduated from Tokyo Zokei University. After working as Yoshiyuki Sadamoto's assistant, he joined Studio MADHOUSE as Production Assistant. After that he had a career change and started working as freelance episode director. He has work experience as episode director in anime such as 'Hanayamata', 'Little Witch Academia', and 'Darling in the FRANXX'.</p>
*By the time this article translated, Nakazono has worked as storyboard artist on SSSS.Gridman and Boogiepop Phantom (2019). \

Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/zonozonu">@zonozonu </a></blockquote>
<h3></h3>
<h3><strong>How do you actually made anime in the first place?</strong></h3>

<hr />

&nbsp;
<p style="text-align:justify;"><em>──</em> To begin with, the three of you also have work today (Saturday) right?</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">(Kojima, Arai, Nakazono): Yes.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#ff6600;">Kojima</span>: Lately I've been losing sleep. Well, I'm okay though, I'll somehow manage it (laugh).</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><em>──</em> So everyday is like a battlefield for you. By the way, the three of you seems getting along well, have the three of you ever worked together before?</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#ff6600;">Kojima</span>: Now that you mention it, we have never worked together before.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><em>──</em> In Illustration (work) field, this is not always the case, but I do get a general impression that people working in anime industry are getting along well. Or perhaps I should say, there's an image that everyone is connected with each other.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#ff6600;">Kojima</span>: This industry actually is a small place, isn't it? If you've enrolled in vocational school or university, then joined anime company you'll eventually met with someone you've known. Also, recently many of us are connected with each other via Twitter.</p>
<em>──</em> Anime industy seems close to illustration industry but actually I think the two of them are fairly different. The craft and workflow are giving totally different impressions. In the first place, there's a job <em>enshutsu </em>which the three of you have experienced before right? What does an <em>enshutsu </em>exactly do?
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#00ff00;">Nakazono</span>: Basically there are two major roles. Drawing storyboards based on the script which is the job of storyboard artist (コンテマン), and matching the consistency of the drawings which is the job of <em>enshutsu</em> (処理演出). Both of them are important jobs. Barikios-san has had the experience of doing both of them at the same time, but recently there are many cases where each part is handled by different person.</p>
<span style="color:#3366ff;">Arai</span>: Also, ensuring the sound match the lip-syncing, making sure to the pose properly succeeds the previous cut...because anime is produced by many people, inconsistency is likely to occur, episode director is the one who acts as coordinator.
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#00ff00;">Nakazono</span>: Storyboard decides the outline of the episode and how the characters move, but episode director job is to make sure the contents of the storyboard are reflected in each cut.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-143" src="https://sakyuuga.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/fix-3.jpg" alt="fix 3" width="617" height="937" /></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#00ff00;">Nakazono</span>: Episode director also received order from Director based on the storyboard such as "I want you to make this scene to look like this". This is called the direction meeting (演打ち/en uchi). After that, episode director will gather the animators for an animation meeting (作打ち/saku uchi), so they can start to draw the layout.</p>
&nbsp;
<h3>The trick to earn a living as an animator is...</h3>

<hr />

&nbsp;
<p style="text-align:justify;"><em>── </em>There's a public opinion that animators only earn a few ten thousand Yen a month, so basically you can't earn a good living. But how is the real condition?</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#00ff00;">Nakazono</span>: That's right. But you will eventually earn a good salary if you got promotion.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#3366ff;">Arai</span>: How about you Kojima-san, when did you start to think "I've finally able to live as an animator"?</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#ff9900;">Kojima</span>: For me it's around the third year after I entered this industry, around the time when I got my first job as animation supervisor on 'Oda Nobuna no Yabou', after that I was given the chance to participate in animation supervision rotation (for Yuyushiki).</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#00ff00;">Nakazono</span>: I'm living by myself right now, but when I just started to work in anime industry I was still living in my parent's house. And I was originally working as Production Assistant which means I've had fixed salary. So I wasn't really in a tight spot for money.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#3366ff;">Arai</span>: When I started my training as in-between animator I only earned around 60,000 Yen a month, but I was able to live in Tokyo because I lived with my parents too.</p>
When I was finally promoted as key animator, basically my earnings are based on work volume. However, there's a thing called <strong>restriction fee </strong>from company or a production (committee). "Please prioritize this work and don't take another job at somewhere else, in exchange we will pay you monthly.", there's a contract like that.
<p style="text-align:justify;">If one is perfectly restrained by this contract and doesn't take other jobs, probably they'll earn around 100,000 ~ 300,000 Yen a month, but if one is taking a semi-restrained contract and allowed to take on other works to certain extent, probably he/she'll earn around 50,000 ~ 150,000 Yen a month.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><em>── </em>Eh, I thought key animation are paid per work volume! But it is certainly will make it easier to live if you have fixed salary right.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#3366ff;">Arai</span>: In order to earn a stable living as animator, restriction fee plays an important part. When I started as newbie key animator, I was able to earn a stable living at once thanks to semi-restrained contract.</p>
<em>──</em> But can anyone get this restriction fee contract once they start as key animator?
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#3366ff;">Arai</span>: No, since it is payment based on someone's ability, if your ability as key animator isn't deemed worthy for the money, they wouldn't offer you the contract. And if you get one but later they think you're not qualified for the contract, you might even lose the contract.</p>
<em>──</em> Is the restraint fee contract only lasted for one <em>cour</em>?
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#ff9900;">Kojima</span>: Yeah. For example, if you get the contract and you're able to participate in a one cour production from the beginning to the end which is usually took around 1 year, basically you will be paid monthly for a year.</p>
<em>──</em> Is the system only introduced recently?
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#ff9900;">Kojima</span>: I don't know the detail, but I think it has existed from long time ago. By the time I came to this industry such a contract already existed.</p>
<span style="color:#00ff00;">Nakazono</span>: There are even people who turn semi-restrained contract into daily job by holding few semi-restrained contracts from multiple companies. Some even hold three or four semi-restrained contracts which raised a question "in what way it is called 'restrained' ?".
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#ff9900;">Kojima</span>: I've never gotten myself a semi-restrained contract, but I'm a bit skeptical about it. I think it's better to commit in a full-restraint contract if you can, it's more healthy for both sides (the production and the animators themselves). Well, I have nothing to say if  one can hold multiple semi-restrained contracts and still be able to perform well.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#3366ff;">Arai</span>: However, <strong>from the viewpoint of animator, I think the best way to earn a living is semi-restrained contract plus remuneration for work volume you've done</strong>. Since if you commit o full-restrain contract you can't take other job.</p>
<span style="color:#00ff00;">Nakazono</span>: Because the restriction fee paid by each company is different, there are many cases where capable people are concentrated at place which pays well.

&nbsp;
<h3>In-betweeners who tend to receive cold treatments should've get a raise</h3>

<hr />

&nbsp;
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#3366ff;">Arai</span>: There are many cases for in-betweeners who don't get restriction fee, moreover there's a condition where they can't guarantee to earn money even though they have the least income among the staff. I think this is should be criticized.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#ff9900;">Kojima</span>: Because most places have a condition "in-betweeners are prohibited to take part time jobs".</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><em>──</em> Part time job is prohibited!? Even though they are not company's employees?</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#3366ff;">Arai</span>: Because most of your day are just drawing (in-betweens), you won't have time for a part time job.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#ff9900;">Kojima</span>: In the first place you can't call that a job right, since in-betweeners' wages are lower than the living wages. On top of that they get harsh treatment by the company such as "don't take part time job!" or "have a sense of responsibility for your job!".</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#3366ff;">Arai</span>: And despite all of that, it's not like in-betweeners drawings are not going to appear to the final picture. There's a reason why this industry is being called "twisted".  (Note: the efforts of in-betweeners are practically can't be seen.)</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#00ff00;">Nakazono</span>: Rather, the part where the production (committee) should expend money the most is in-between, and then key animation. There's a sense of crisis that if such a condition isn't improved, the situation will be even more declining.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Kojima: Recently the number of companies which pay the restraint fee are increasing, and there are several places where they give high treatment to their employees too.</p>

<h3 style="text-align:justify;">Has Anime Industry made more money?</h3>

<hr />
<p style="text-align:justify;"><em>── </em>Recently there are many titles that are going to be added to streaming service's catalogs like Netflix and Amazon Prime. Also I heard anime industry has became richer thanks to foreign investors pouring a lot of money too, but how is the actual condition?</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#00ff00;">Nakazono</span>: Simply put, at the level of our working environment, there's no such a thing as rapid increase in our wages. The unit price for key animation has increased about 10~20% though.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><em>── </em>So little! I thought the increase had to be around 10 times since the media made a huge deal about this news.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#00ff00;">Nakazono</span>: Even if you say the source of the budget has increased, it's not like the money floating around are going to end up at animators, the budget are going to rotate around the editing and sound recording and reproduction. Because if we're talking about anime funded by foreign investment, a large percentage of the budget are going to be used for editing and sound recording and reproduction.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#ff9900;">Kojima</span>: Yeah, since in the case of anime (intended for) international streaming services there's also dubbed version, so the cost for editing and dubbing will be much higher than TV anime.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><em>── </em>You mentioned editing, but can you elaborate more what kind of part is going to be edited?</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#00ff00;">Nakazono</span>: Editing is a finishing process that requested to a company outside of anime studio. The work entails editing and putting together the work into a final product that will fit the time slot given by TV station, in this case is 21 minutes.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Editing is a role that makes a pleasant flow of the video according to a fixed length, from the viewpoint of the whole process the importance of this role rises.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Therefore, <strong>editing is not paid per unit work but the charge rates are increasing according to the length of the work</strong>. In other words, the longer the length of the work is, the more money the production committee has to pay※.  And since editing companies are outside of anime industry, the standard prices are higher if you compared it with anime industry's standard.</p>
※ But in recent years, the number of editing companies that take the job on fixed charge rates (not based on the length of the work) have increased.

<span style="color:#00ff00;">Nakazono</span>: There are anime studios that have their own editing departments, but only a small handful of studios that have such a privilege.

<span style="color:#3366ff;">Arai</span>: Since editing work is basically always outsourced, obviously it's going to take its toll on the production side.

<em>── </em>And why from animators do not raise their voices for labor negotiations and wage increases?

<span style="color:#3366ff;">Arai</span>: It's because most of us are freelancers who scattered around many places, to make an union is difficult. Also, I think it's because the lack of interest in organizing a labor reform or negotiation. Such a proactive person who could think of that (organizing labor reform or negotiation) wouldn't choose animator as their profession in the first place.

<span style="color:#ff9900;">Kojima</span>: Anyway it's because we're so busy to the point we're to tired to use our physical strength for other than our work. Therefore there are many people who just gave up and quit their work without negotiating.

&nbsp;
<h3><strong>The number of young animators keeps increasing, widening the gap of technical skill </strong></h3>

<hr />

<em>── </em>All of you were starting this career from such young ages and then started advancing to mid-level right? (tl note: such as Animation Director, Episode Director). Do you feel a sense of crisis in today's industry like, a lot of newbie animators are quitting their job?

<span style="color:#3366ff;">Arai</span>: No, I think it's the opposite, more and more new talents are coming into this industry.

<em>── </em>That's unexpected. Why do you think they're coming into animation industry?

<span style="color:#3366ff;">Arai</span>: As for me, I was influenced by <em>ugomemo</em> movement.

Note: <em>ugomemo </em>(うごメモ) or <i>Ugoku Memochō</i> (<span lang="ja">うごくメモ帳) is a free downloadable application for drawing by Nintendo DS. First released in 2008, the software lets the user to draw picture and animation through its stylus. The successor of this application is <i>Ugoku Memochō</i> 3D (うごくメモ帳3D) which is released for Nintendo 3DS. The app is alsow known as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flipnote_Studio">Flipnote Studio 3D</a>. </span>

<em>── </em>Ugomemo?

<span style="color:#ff9900;">Kojima</span>: The person who draws for <em>Ugomemo</em> promotional video was debuted from Kyoto Animation, and she's incredibly good. (Referring to <a href="https://twitter.com/PurpleGeth/status/1038478834000121857">Tomoe Aratani</a>, former Kyoto Animator animator who joined Nintendo in 2010).
<p style="text-align:center;">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tOEyehYBrT0</p>
&nbsp;

<em>── </em>I didn't know about this. Certainly the number of young animators who were inspired by this movement and coming into animation industry could be increasing.

With the widespread use of digital tools nowadays, the hurdles for animation production are getting lower. That's because the number of people who are used to draw with their pen tablets since childhood is increasing, and the age-group of people who are getting interested with this industry also keeps getting younger.

Since the sooner you started drawing the better you will be, I think the skill of newcomers are really good these days.

<span style="color:#ff9900;">Kojima</span>: I think the benefit of (owning) digital equipment is quite significant but on the other hand people who have no motivation still wouldn't get better at honing their skills even they have good equipment.

I had the chance to attend a vocational school and everyone there owned smartphone but I barely saw anyone who make use of their smartphone when creating animation.

<em>── </em>How do use it, for example?

<span style="color:#ff9900;">Kojima</span>: For example you could take pictures for drawing references, or making a short movie by moving your still pictures. I think there are a lot of application that can do that short of things.

<em>── </em>That's because you can also do video editing using smartphone applications nowadays right.

<span style="color:#ff9900;">Kojima</span>: <strong>I think the problem lies on the person themselves. Even though more and more tools are increasing, people who don't have the motivation wouldn't even try to make use of it, and in the end they're getting further left behind by the rest of people who are learning to use it. </strong>And it applies not only in animation industry, but illustration or modelling industry too. There was no such a convenient tool like smartphone in the past, but people still make the best of available technology, even drawing from their <a href="http://www.japansubculture.com/the-cell-phone-from-galapagos-japans-gara-kei-%E3%82%AC%E3%83%A9%E3%82%B1%E3%83%BC%E3%80%80/"><em>gara-kei</em>'</a>s low resolution screen<em>. </em>

<span style="color:#3366ff;">Arai</span>: I see. <del>Even saying "let's buy better tools", or "it will be easier if I have this tool!", but in the end people who don't have the motivation still wouldn't try to and people who have the motivation will earnestly</del> People who said "I'll upgrade my tools to get better" or "it will be easier for me if I have this tool!", in the end those who don't have the motivation still wouldn't put more effort than needed, and people who got the motivation will work extra hard no matter what.

<span style="color:#ff9900;">Kojima</span>: Actually at the company I'm also in charge of training fresh recruits, but it made me re-think about some things and I came into conclusion that "people who aren't interested (in animation) won't survive in this industry!".

As for simple things like paperwork is easy to be taught, but it's tough to get better at drawing<em> </em>and other technical things just by following training course. I'm working hard to rise the motivation among new recruits, but it's quite difficult.

&nbsp;
<h3>"Cheap and fast" the reason why foreign animators come in handy in anime production</h3>

<hr />

<em>── </em>I noticed a lot of foreign names like Koreans and Chinese when I see credit rolls. Has the number of outsourced works increased lately?

<span style="color:#3366ff;">Arai</span>: I don't know what it was like in the past, but right now, as for in-between works, mostly they're outsourced to overseas studio. I heard that around 90% of the in-between for anime produced in Japan are drawn by people from abroad.

<em>──</em> 90%

<span style="color:#ff9900;">Kojima</span>: <strong>That's because they (overseas studio) are always finished their work in time</strong>. I don't know how they operate though.

<span style="color:#00ff00;">Nakazono</span>: <strong>In the case of China, it seems they completely divide the working tasks into specialized occupation</strong>. Unlike in Japan where one builds their career from in-between → key animation → animation supervision, it seems they have people who specialized in certain fields and each person decides their career, like in which area are they going to focus on professionally.

<span style="color:#ff9900;">Kojima</span>: It depends on the schedule, but there are cases where the studio outsourced the in-between works to overseas studio even though they have in-house their own in-between animators, and this resulted in job opportunities for domestic in-between animators declining.

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>132</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2019-02-23 07:53:42</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name/>
  <wp:status>draft</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_065bc68e6e1b1ae5ac0c7e39a6128c3f</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_5d4d3ba45534bb6a28e795e188e6431d</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>fix 3</title>
  <link>https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/?attachment_id=143</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 07:46:45 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>kyuudere</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://sakyuuga.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/fix-3.jpg</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>143</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2018-08-13 07:46:45</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2018-08-13 07:46:45</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>closed</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>fix-3</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>132</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://sakyuuga.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/fix-3.jpg</wp:attachment_url>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Studio Colorido's First Feature Film, Challenge and Future of Digital Tools Usage</title>
  <link>https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/?p=146</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov -0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>kyuudere</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/?p=146</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[This is a rough translation of an interview published by anime!anime! site, which you can read here:

https://animeanime.jp/article/2018/08/13/39432.html

&nbsp;
<h3>What kind of digital environment did you face when producing your first feature length film?</h3>

<hr />

―In your first film, "Hinata no Aoshigure", you said in our interview that the film were produced in both analog/paper and digital. How about "Penguin Highway", in what kind of set-up and environment it was produced?

Ishida: Certainly there's a point that Hinata no Aoshigure's production was a mix between analog and digital, in the end it still remains in Penguin Highway. Actually there's still much left lol.]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>146</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2018-09-24 05:47:25</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name/>
  <wp:status>draft</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_28e995e24df5d743450b4433eae596d3</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Understanding Kagenashi Style</title>
  <link>https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/?p=171</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov -0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>kyuudere</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/?p=171</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
	<li>
<ul>
	<li>The art of shadow and lighting in Japanese Cinema -&gt; ???</li>
	<li>The correlation between Japanese Cinema and Anime (Hosoda's theatrical anime film) -&gt; ???</li>
	<li>The web generation movement's roles in developing "kagenashi style"</li>
	<li>Artistic value of "kagenashi style" in modern anime</li>
</ul>
Related anime:

Jin Roh?
Takashi Nakamura?

Several Hosoda Mamoru's work: Digimon episode 20, Digimon OVA/Movie?, One Piece Movie 6, Toki wo Kakeru Shoujo, Summer Wars, Okami Kodomo to Ame no Yuki, Bakemono no Ko, Mirai no Mirai

Masashi Ishihama's work: Shinsekai Yori

Shingo Yamashita's work: CM, OP/ED,

Web gen movement

Masaaki Yuasa? Tatami Galaxy, Ping Pong -&gt; Simple???

Naoko Yamada??? -&gt; Koe no Katachi

Aku no Hana?

Showa Genraku

Mononoke -&gt; Art house???

PSG??? Power Puff Girls???

Kenji Nakamura?

&nbsp;

Possible relation? -&gt; Wakame Shadow

<b>ワカメ影</b>

https://www18.atwiki.jp/sakuga/pages/28.html

80年台後半から90年初頭の作品で多々見られる影。似た形状のハイライトの表現も見られる。00年代~10年代初頭には新井淳がこの手法を用いた。
スタジオZ5の亀垣一や平山智が「鉄人２８号(1979)」や「ゴッドマーズ」で使ったトレス主線に沿わずにだんだら模様に影をつけ、
それに沿うような形でそれよりも細い影を入れる手法が代表的な例。
これらは「ヤマト」や「９９９」の金田伊功の影やハイライトの表現がルーツの一つとされ、
俗に「ワカメ影」「メタリック影」「Z5影」「だんだら」とも呼ばれた。
これとは別のルーツで派生したと思われる、上記の影、ハイライトと比較的近い形状の「超時空要塞マクロス」等で見られた
ハイディテールな影、ハイライト表現も一緒くたに「ワカメ影」と呼ばれることがある。
似た手法として太い直線影（ハイライト）に沿うような形で細い直線影（ハイライト）を入れるものがある（Zガンダム当時の内田順久が代表的な例）。

「ワカメ影」という名称は80年代当時からの名称ではなく、後年出来たものという説がある。
佐野浩敏、大張正己の両氏は、80年代の自身の作画における影表現を「デザイン影」と当時呼んでいたそう。
（具体的にどの時期のスタイルの影表現を差しているかは不明）
これとは別に「バブルガム・クライシス」のハードスーツや「戦え！イクサー1」の富士参号（FJ-Ⅲ）に付く、
BLやハイライトがヌラッとしたような影を「メタリック影」と呼んでいたと、大張正己は語っている。<a href="https://togetter.com/li/167517">詳しくはこちら</a>。
「うる星やつら」で山下将仁が描く戦車や飛行機の影もワカメ影的な手法の代表例とされることも多いが、
「オトナアニメCOLLECTION　いまだから語れる80年代アニメ秘話～スーパーロボットの時代～」によれば本人は否定している。

References:

http://www.style.fm/as/13_special/hosoda_ou_bokura.shtml

http://www.style.fm/log/01_talk/nakamura03.html

http://www.style.fm/as/01_talk/okiura05.shtml

http://www.style.fm/as/01_talk/okiura06.shtml

http://animestyle.jp/2012/11/08/2977/ (Shinsekai Yori)

http://www.style.fm/as/01_talk/mihara03.shtml

&nbsp;

Interview log:

http://www.style.fm/log/01_talk_m.html

Related readings:

https://detail.chiebukuro.yahoo.co.jp/qa/question_detail/q13164749388

http://anicobin.ldblog.jp/archives/38805127.html

http://anicobin.ldblog.jp/archives/46158124.html

http://nipponia.blog44.fc2.com/blog-entry-196.html?sp</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>171</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2018-11-21 08:59:38</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name/>
  <wp:status>draft</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_991012e4a337221c3e7de0823017bd6d</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_d82772fbb8222345bc24d8cb3f228ed8</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_771596124d55f1ae94dce8b7bbcc0245</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_62968b0cde5bca8da80bf7710a87b8fa</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_2fcc08aedcf7dffa0628a7574a2895e4</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_114d076a726c1521c8fbb32f47836e88</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_609c377eee37498a9724cc49a3d10105</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_a2306a41a5e24fbe4b1894d126ad2290</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_f8f47c6acfd75fd1dffdfa757d9a0638</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_43383e5e96ee8efabeddad0946919e67</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Matsumoto Rie is back ~I Love You da ze!~</title>
  <link>https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/2019/02/24/__trashed-3/</link>
  <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 03:16:44 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>kyuudere</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/?p=173</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[Matsumoto Rie (Kyousougiga, Kekkai Sensen) has just making her comeback with Yuki Hayashi (Kyousougiga) in a music video collaboration with Bump of Chicken (Kekkai Sensen) to celebrate 70th anniversary of Lotte.

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>173</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2019-02-24 03:16:44</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2019-02-24 03:16:44</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>__trashed-3</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>trash</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wp_trash_meta_status</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[draft]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wp_trash_meta_time</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1550978204]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wp_desired_post_slug</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>An End-of-Year Retrospective to Myself</title>
  <link>https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/2018/12/31/an-end-of-year-retrospective-to-myself/</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 04:59:25 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>kyuudere</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/?p=175</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[I've been in a slump this week, no maybe this whole year. I had intended to publish some articles (translation, opinion, etc) in the second half of 2018, I already made some drafts but in the end I never got to finish them and only able to publish two (crappy) translations for this blog. I thought I'd finally get serious with this blog thing, but the struggle is real. I felt like I had no confidence in my writing skills at all and it made me so nervous whenever I tried to write an opinion (and that's why I chose to publish some lousy translation rather than my own article). On a positive note, the number of anime I had seen this year have increased from last year. I also managed to drag my lazy ass to watch two anime movies that coming to our local theaters, so I guess that was an accomplishment in its own. There were a lot of great movies coming this year and even though there were only a handful of number that made it here, I'm glad that the enthusiasm of anime fans for licensed movies haven't died here. We even had a big event, <a href="https://jcinema2018.id/">Japan Cinema Week 2018</a> which brought some high profile anime movies like Miss Hokusai, The Tale of Princess Kaguya, Mary and the Witch's Flower and even <a href="https://jcinema2018.id/films/ponoc.php">Ponoc's short films</a>. Sadly I wasn't able to go to the event, which was held pretty far from where I live. Had it been held in my city I'd totally go to the event.

To put it short, if there is a word to describe how I felt about my accomplishment in this year, it would be 'regret'. I regretted I didn't watch more anime even though I clearly had more free time, it was also vexing that I wasn't able to participate in sakugabowl this year even though Kevin has kindly reached me through twitter, I'm really honored. But the fault is mine, I feel like I need to address an apology that I wasn't able to made it in time since I'm still struggling to finish some anime that I've been putting on hold. Once I finished mine I guess I'll post here, of course if they don't mind if I took the same format for the nomination.

By the way, I'm really excited to see some new faces on <a href="https://blog.sakugabooru.com/2018/12/30/a-look-at-the-sakuga-and-animation-of-2018/">sakugabowl this year</a>! Animeblue, Ryan, braves, paeses who were on last year's sakugabowl aren't there, it seems some sakuga senpai are passing the baton to new writers, like Ryan who said <a href="https://twitter.com/Disgaeamad/status/1073374059453444100">he has stepped down from sakuga blog's activity</a>...thank you for all the hard works, I'm sure you'll be back when there's more imas anime :') On the bright side, I finally got to see Ashita, Diamond, Osama...and I heard the sakugablog also have invited the king of sakubuta, <a href="https://twitter.com/ky_shinzanmono">shinzanmono</a>-san, but it seemed he was too busy. Also, I'm eager to see some opinion on this year's animation from enthusiastic fans like <a href="https://twitter.com/Bloodyredstar">Blou</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/FARfromani">FARFromAni</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/HiMyNameisChair">Chair</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/Purple_Geth">PurpleGeth</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/Agresiel">Agresiel</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/vanjiilost">vanjiilost</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/RonSnow_0">Ron,</a> and probably many more. It's nice to see the Japanese sakubuta also celebrated the year in their own ways, be it in a listicle form of best anime <a href="http://shirooo305.hatenablog.com/entry/2018/12/24/115530">opening</a> and <a href="http://shirooo305.hatenablog.com/entry/2018/12/26/172912">ending</a>, or a <a href="https://twitter.com/oretaka/status/1078223305448992769">meme douga</a> like what oretaka-san has always been doing. They're really entertaining and educative as always. All in all, I really enjoyed being in this community, thank you for people who have followed me, I didn't know what you saw in me when clicking that follow button, but well....I'll work harder to be a proper sakuga fans next year too.

This year has been really exhilarating adventure too, we got to see many new creative forces making their way out from twitter to anime industry like their recent effort in <a href="https://blog.sakugabooru.com/2018/12/19/black-clover-63/">Black Clover #63</a>. Props to <a href="https://blog.sakugabooru.com/2018/05/20/a-new-wave-of-worldwide-animators-reaches-anime-to-be-heroine-staff-interview/">foreign webgen animators</a> who made <a href="https://blog.sakugabooru.com/2018/07/22/the-power-of-international-intergenerational-anime-boruto-65/">a big splash</a> in Japanese anime industry too! Many thanks for them and I hope they'll keep improving!

To end this somewhat solemn post, let me thank you for reading my blog. Have a happy new year!
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-176" src="https://sakyuuga.files.wordpress.com/2018/12/ありがとな.jpg" alt="ありがとな" width="1024" height="576" /></p>
&nbsp;

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>175</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2018-12-31 04:59:25</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2018-12-31 04:59:25</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>an-end-of-year-retrospective-to-myself</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_28b888abf2f941afbee8ae102be04748</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-twitter"><a class="twitter-moment" data-width="500" data-dnt="true" href="https://twitter.com/i/moments/1090957633794715653?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">新文芸坐×アニメスタイル セレクションVol. 111 押井守映画祭2019 第二夜〈天使のたまご&amp;御先祖様〉編</a><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1546232368]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[-1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[26018468420]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_28b888abf2f941afbee8ae102be04748</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1549449330]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_96687d763f56cc0c1553c7c106b13bd9</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-twitter"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="ja" dir="ltr">押井守映画祭トーク終了しました！<br>ご来場いただいた皆様ありがとうございました！<br>まるでペアルックの押井監督と西尾さん<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/%E6%8A%BC%E4%BA%95%E5%AE%88?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#押井守</a> <a href="https://t.co/n4an9wG4PV">pic.twitter.com/n4an9wG4PV</a></p>&mdash; 押井守 公式アカウント (@oshii_mamoru) <a href="https://twitter.com/oshii_mamoru/status/1089172377567555584?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 26, 2019</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_96687d763f56cc0c1553c7c106b13bd9</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1549449550]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>ありがとな</title>
  <link>https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/2018/12/31/an-end-of-year-retrospective-to-myself/%e3%81%82%e3%82%8a%e3%81%8c%e3%81%a8%e3%81%aa/</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 04:58:42 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>kyuudere</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://sakyuuga.files.wordpress.com/2018/12/ありがとな.jpg</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>176</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2018-12-31 04:58:42</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2018-12-31 04:58:42</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>closed</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>%e3%81%82%e3%82%8a%e3%81%8c%e3%81%a8%e3%81%aa</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>175</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://sakyuuga.files.wordpress.com/2018/12/ありがとな.jpg</wp:attachment_url>
</item>
<item>
  <title>What to look forward in 2019 (Winter)</title>
  <link>https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/2019/02/07/__trashed/</link>
  <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 04:39:32 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>kyuudere</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/?p=178</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>178</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2019-02-07 04:39:32</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2019-02-07 04:39:32</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>__trashed</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>trash</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wp_trash_meta_status</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[draft]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wp_trash_meta_time</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1549514372]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wp_desired_post_slug</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title/>
  <link>https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/2019/02/07/__trashed-2/</link>
  <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 04:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>kyuudere</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/?p=179</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[Happy New Year!

&nbsp;

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>179</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2019-02-07 04:39:40</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2019-02-07 04:39:40</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>__trashed-2</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>trash</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wp_trash_meta_status</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[draft]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wp_trash_meta_time</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1549514380]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wp_desired_post_slug</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Mamoru Oshii Film Festival 2019</title>
  <link>https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/2019/02/06/mamoru-oshii-film-festival-2019/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 10:47:33 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>kyuudere</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://sakyuuga.wordpress.com/?p=180</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[&nbsp;

Another translation of Anime Style event report titled "Mamoru Oshii Film Festival 2019: The second Night", courtesy of YnkL-san. This time <a href="https://twitter.com/shin_bungeiza">Shin-Bungeiza</a> collaborated with Anime Style's <a href="https://twitter.com/animesama">Yuichiro Oguro </a>again to held this event in which they sat down with Mamoru Oshii and Tetsuya Nishio to discuss Angel's Egg and Gosenzosama Banbanzai! They shared some production excerpts, funny stories and their struggle during the production, also of course Oshii's outspoken personality is always charming in its own way.

https://twitter.com/oshii_mamoru/status/1089172377567555584

<em>Oshii (right) and Nishio (left) were posing in a picture they taken together after the event. </em>

Credits: This translation wouldn't be possibly made without the wonderful event report by ynkl-san, so much all the credit goes to him. Also thanks for few anons from DJT who helped me to understand few paragraphs.

This translation was by no means perfect, I had only it done in few hours so if you notice some translation errors/grammatical mistakes, I apologize! And feel free to left it out at the comment.

<a href="https://twitter.com/i/moments/1090957633794715653">Original tweets by ynkl-san</a>

Note: There's a mistake which he puts yagate kimi ni naru's bd commentary tweet in those moment so I re-arranged them into pastebin text.

https://pastebin.com/3ZxiSswG

====

<span style="color:#99ccff;"><em><strong>Topic: Angel's Egg</strong></em></span>

<strong>Nishio</strong>: Angel's Egg was only 70-minutes long, relatively short work for a feature length movie, so people who fall asleep when watching it really have low literacy, don't they? Visually speaking, there are a lot of stimulus in it and the music is very dramatic, it's totally watchable.

<strong>Oshii</strong>: I don't mind people fell asleep at all. Since I wanted to emulate that Tarkovskian atmosphere in animation form. A pleasant and unbounded time. Films that make people fall asleep are good films.

<strong>Nishio</strong>: Is it a good thing or a bad thing?

<strong>Oshii:</strong> Feeling sleepy when watching a film is a good thing. It's a proof that your brain is synchronizing with the film.

<span style="color:#99ccff;"><em><strong>The Production excerpts of Angel's Egg</strong></em></span>

<strong>Oshii:</strong> The in-betweening process was like a hell. Especially the girl's hair. It took us 3 months just to finish that 1 cut of the <a href="https://twitter.com/rob_0815/status/776411449635680256">tank scene</a>. The staff were young and energetic so I thought that they could pull it off somehow. It was that kind of work where the animators can't make it out without seeing hell themselves.

<strong>Nishio:</strong> There were some Ghibli's starting member weren't there? Like color designer (Michiyo) Yasuda-san and the producer (Toshio) Suzuki-san.

<strong>Oshii:</strong> I had good relationship with Ghibli back in those days. They even lent me Makiko Futaki-chan for more than 6 months. Yasuda-san and me had a quarrel to the point it was so loud and everyone could hear us from the hallway. In the end we both settled down on the matter though.

<strong>Oshii:</strong> By the way Anno even ran away from us for three weeks. We had this kind of atmosphere where we were like bunch of trainee monks meditating, Anno had it enough and said "I hate being in a monastery-like place like this!" then ran away.

<strong>Oshii:</strong> I constructed this movie as to be easy to understood its message if you finished it until the end. It's not something that you must dwell over or look into it too hard. Angel's egg has a structure but it has no story.

<span style="color:#99ccff;"><em><strong>Topic: Gosenzosama Banbanzai!</strong></em></span>

<strong>Oshii:</strong> It was a total flop. We didn't have that much budget but we still made it so the music was so rich. I was working in the studio as if I were in a two-man band (I worked really hard and stayed up till morning in studio's hallway).

<strong>Oshii:</strong> Pierrot's President (Ichikawa-san) told me to make something like Urusei Yatsura, and I told them "what if we make Lum-chan as a swindler?" and the producer was like, so troubled with my idea. If it's too normal it would be discontinued in just two episodes right?

<span style="color:#99ccff;"><em><strong>Topic: Gosenzosama Banbanzai! shock</strong></em></span>

<strong>Nishio:</strong> It was a turning point in my life. I was so influenced by its maniacal work.

<strong>Oshii:</strong> I'm glad it was well received among animators.

<strong>Oshii:</strong> There were a lot of different animators in this anime, if you think about it now, they were all would eventually be big names in this industry.

<strong>Nishio:</strong> Technically speaking episode 4 was the peak (of art).

<strong>Oshii:</strong> By episode 6 the situation was like a car with flat tires. The in-between weren't very good but the key animation was great so we somehow managed to pull it off. I had Kise to draw around 8 cuts. Gosenzosama Banbanzai had like, 60-70 cuts per episode. The character acting cuts were very long and it was very difficult to animate them. We used around 20-30 sheets of background too.

<strong>Nishio:</strong> You had to use a box to carry around them instead of normal bag right.

<strong>Oshii:</strong> Yeah, they wouldn't possibly fit in normal bags. At the time although we were competing with other OVAs we didn't have much money so we didn't have such a leeway to do wasteful things. Originally the character designer wasn't (Satoru) Utsunomiya, the plan was to hire someone from Gainax but they ran away. Even Masayuki ran away from me.

<span style="color:#99ccff;"><em><strong>Topic: The Sky Crawlers</strong></em></span>

<strong>Oshii:</strong> It was my last work as anime director and I haven't got around to direct anything since then.

<strong>Nishio:</strong> You could feel like the flow of this industry (animation) really changed right?

<strong>Oshii:</strong> Yeah, right now there isn't any single project that I proposed got accepted and my wife told me "It's not your era". But it's not like I came to hate anime or I don't want to direct anime again, even now I still have one (or two?) project that I'm really working hard for.

<strong>Nishio:</strong> Sky Crawlers was my last job in my 30s. And without realizing it, now the number of younger anime directors that I worked with grew. If the director were older than me it would be easy for me to chew them out, but now they're all younger and if I were to do that it would be called power harassment.

<strong>Oshii:</strong> Sky Crawlers was closer to a literary film. I wanted to focus on the character acting when they were on the ground and if I have to be honest, it'd be better if the aerial combat scene were cut off. In fact, the CG aerial combat was awesome but the character's expression was meh.

<span style="color:#99ccff;"><em><strong>Topic: Character acting</strong></em></span>

<strong>Oshii:</strong> "The point of character acting (in Sky Crawler) is to make it doesn't feel like a character acting at all.", Tettsun (Nishio Tetsuya's nickname) and I discussed it for so many times. "Don't make them move, but don't stop them either."  But then how do we create the sense of realism? Should we make it a work just entirely about people? Actually I felt a big sense of accomplishment because we made it work, I liked it the most.

<strong>Nishio:</strong> The design was well received among animators we worked with because they were simple. My reputation also sky-rocketed thanks to it. I absolutely couldn't let myself collapse after the production of Sky Crawlers ended, but in itself you can say I worked too hard on myself.

<strong>Oshii:</strong> As for me, I was goofing at work as much as it deemed appropriate. Usually when I re-drew and fixing the layout I had to drew all like the character and as such, but since Sky Crawlers was mostly on eye level shot, once I drew some minor correction my job is finished. I leave the rest of work to Tettsun.

<strong>Nishio:</strong> Yeah, you often weren't around in the studio.

<strong>Oshii:</strong> It's because I can't draw, I would just be a nuisance if I was there. Also, I completely trust Tettsun so Sky Crawlers is almost completely Tettsun's work.

<strong>Oshii:</strong> From animation perspective, I'm really satisfied with Sky Crawlers. I want to illustrate the character's existence through the their acting which flows naturally like the flow of time itself. I requested to make the character feels like they're real people who actually stand on the same ground as us. This can't be done other by the animation supervisor (sakkan). I want the audience to pay attention how the characters open and fold newspaper, also the gorgeous bowling scene by Shishou (Takeshi Honda). Also the scene Kise drew, it was so incredibly amorous.

<span style="color:#99ccff;"><strong><em>Topic: Production I.G.</em></strong></span>

<strong>Oshii:</strong> It surely has been a while since I was at I.G, now there are only names and faces I don't recognize there. Also the studio is oddly so quiet now.

<strong>Nishio:</strong> Now there are no one left but young female staff at I.G.

<strong>Oshii:</strong> When we were working on Sky Crawlers we did bunch of stuff like drinking or making oden and got chewed out real bad, didn't we? Now I can't feel such an atmosphere at I.G.

<strong>Nishio:</strong> I remember I was hiding Sukiyaki pot under my table.

<strong>Oshii:</strong> Right now there's almost no merit when making anime in large group like back then when we did it in such a festive atmosphere. We still had it back then during Sky Crawlers, when Shishou had Pizza party at the studio he also wouldn't come in and just peeked in.

<strong>Nishio:</strong> Our young staff were like "Inoue? Shishou? Who are they?"

<em><strong><span style="color:#99ccff;">Oshii's on Tetsuya Nishio</span></strong></em>

<strong>Oshii:</strong> A Superman. He can do anything. Very diligent and always keeping up with deadlines. Because he has a strong sense of responsibility he often complained and chewed out the staff, but when he's glued to the desk he's really dependable. On the contrary Kise is really a problem child, like if you don't keep your eyes on him, he'll run away to play at other people's apartment or game center, on the contrary this often makes Tettsun feel agitated.

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>180</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2019-02-06 10:47:33</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2019-02-06 10:47:33</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>mamoru-oshii-film-festival-2019</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="angels-egg"><![CDATA[Angel's Egg]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="anime-style"><![CDATA[Anime Style]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="event-report"><![CDATA[Event Report]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="gosenzosama-banbanzai"><![CDATA[Gosenzosama Banbanzai!]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="kuso-translation"><![CDATA[kuso translation]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="mamoru-oshii"><![CDATA[Mamoru Oshii]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="production-i-g"><![CDATA[Production I.G.]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="tetsuya-nishio"><![CDATA[Tetsuya Nishio]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_80f62eebef5f0c7b6ae90f22ee69d564</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_bb091e45d4687b711ebb5a44d5845773</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-twitter"><a class="twitter-moment" data-width="840" data-dnt="true" href="https://twitter.com/i/moments/1090957633794715653?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">新文芸坐×アニメスタイル セレクションVol. 111 押井守映画祭2019 第二夜〈天使のたまご&amp;御先祖様〉編</a><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_bb091e45d4687b711ebb5a44d5845773</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1549449409]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_9dab7d1162b5c8fa2cb99d96588ebeb6</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_3ba41f1f9a1c953c8e111d239207853b</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-twitter"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="ja" dir="ltr">押井守映画祭トーク終了しました！<br>ご来場いただいた皆様ありがとうございました！<br>まるでペアルックの押井監督と西尾さん<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/%E6%8A%BC%E4%BA%95%E5%AE%88?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#押井守</a> <a href="https://t.co/n4an9wG4PV">pic.twitter.com/n4an9wG4PV</a></p>&mdash; 押井守 公式アカウント (@oshii_mamoru) <a href="https://twitter.com/oshii_mamoru/status/1089172377567555584?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 26, 2019</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_3ba41f1f9a1c953c8e111d239207853b</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1549449687]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_9edd8ff75b76cd69f9fcb3ee80a345a0</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_96687d763f56cc0c1553c7c106b13bd9</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-twitter"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="ja" dir="ltr">押井守映画祭トーク終了しました！<br>ご来場いただいた皆様ありがとうございました！<br>まるでペアルックの押井監督と西尾さん<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/%E6%8A%BC%E4%BA%95%E5%AE%88?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#押井守</a> <a href="https://t.co/n4an9wG4PV">pic.twitter.com/n4an9wG4PV</a></p>&mdash; 押井守 公式アカウント (@oshii_mamoru) <a href="https://twitter.com/oshii_mamoru/status/1089172377567555584?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 26, 2019</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_962b961b28093007db34ed9ba4bdaf01</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-twitter"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="ja" dir="ltr">押井守映画祭トーク終了しました！<br>ご来場いただいた皆様ありがとうございました！<br>まるでペアルックの押井監督と西尾さん<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/%E6%8A%BC%E4%BA%95%E5%AE%88?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#押井守</a> <a href="https://t.co/n4an9wG4PV">pic.twitter.com/n4an9wG4PV</a></p>&mdash; 押井守 公式アカウント (@oshii_mamoru) <a href="https://twitter.com/oshii_mamoru/status/1089172377567555584?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 26, 2019</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_962b961b28093007db34ed9ba4bdaf01</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1549450063]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_b1b6affd12a0925e7cf591bea5225afb</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1549450064]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[-1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[27338873037]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_5dafd9d67af68a864cebcdd1c7c0e09f</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<div class="embed-twitter"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="ja" dir="ltr">押井守映画祭トーク終了しました！<br>ご来場いただいた皆様ありがとうございました！<br>まるでペアルックの押井監督と西尾さん<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/%E6%8A%BC%E4%BA%95%E5%AE%88?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#押井守</a> <a href="https://t.co/n4an9wG4PV">pic.twitter.com/n4an9wG4PV</a></p>&mdash; 押井守 公式アカウント (@oshii_mamoru) <a href="https://twitter.com/oshii_mamoru/status/1089172377567555584?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 26, 2019</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_5dafd9d67af68a864cebcdd1c7c0e09f</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1549450066]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_96687d763f56cc0c1553c7c106b13bd9</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1549450258]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_014855a5241a8ba52ccd530bad9a58e0</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
  </channel>
</rss>
